AND LOOK ALL RIGHT GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYONE.
WELCOME TO THE OCTOBER 7TH 2025 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL? >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHEN PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY PRESENT SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO
AND ENGARDIO PRESENT SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER NOT PRESENT
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD PRESENT SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN
PRESIDENT MANDOLIN PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR
PRESENT SUPERVISOR SAUTER SADR PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHERYL
CHERYL PRESENT AND SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON PRESENT.
MR. PRESIDENT YOU HAVE A QUORUM .
THANK YOU MADAM CLERK THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
ACKNOWLEDGES THAT WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL HOMELAND OF
THE RAW ALONI WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PENINSULA. AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF
THIS LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE
RAMAKRISHNA LOAN WE HAVE NEVER CEDED LOST OR FORGOTTEN THEIR
RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS
WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL
IN THEIR TRADITIONAL TERRITORY. AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE
BENEFIT FROM LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELAND.
WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS,
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE RAW MATERIALS AND COMMUNITY AND BY
AFFIRMING THEIR SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST PEOPLES.
>> COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF
ALLEGIANCE TO PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG OF THE UNITED
STATES OF AMERICA AND TO THE REPUBLIC FOR WHICH IT STANDS
ONE NATION UNDER GOD WITH VISIBLE LIBERTY AND JUSTICE FOR
ALL. >> ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I
WOULD LIKE TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF OF S.F. GOV TV TODAY THAT
IS ESPECIALLY KALEENA MENDOZA. THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR
MEETINGS AND MAKE THE TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE
PUBLIC ONLINE. MADAM CLERK, DO YOU HAVE ANY
COMMUNICATIONS? >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WELCOMES YOU ALL TO
ATTEND THIS MEETING IN PERSON HERE IN THE BOARD'S LEGISLATIVE
CHAMBER SECOND FLOOR OF CITY HALL ROOM 250.
IF YOU'RE UNABLE TO MAKE IT IN PERSON YOU CAN ALWAYS WATCH
THE PROCEEDINGS ON AS OF GOVEE TVS CHANNEL 26 OR VIEW THE
LIVESTREAM AT W W W DOT S.F. GEO VTV.ORG IF YOU HAVE PUBLIC
COMMENT AND YOU'D LIKE TO SUBMIT IT YOU CAN SEND AN EMAIL
TO B O S AT S.F. GOV.ORG OR USE THE U.S. POSTAL SERVICE.
JUST ADDRESS THE ENVELOPE TO THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. >> THE NUMBER ONE DR. CARLTON B
GOODLATTE PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244 SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA
94102 IF YOU NEED TO MAKE A REASONABLE ACCOMMODATION
REQUEST UNDER THE AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT OR TO
REQUEST LANGUAGE ASSISTANCE, YOU CAN CALL THE CLERK'S OFFICE
AT (415) 554-5184. >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. LET'S GO TO APPROVAL OF OUR
MEETING MINUTES. THIS WOULD BE FOR APPROVAL OF
THE SEPTEMBER 2ND, 2025 BOARD MEETING MINUTES.
>> ALL RIGHT. COULD I HAVE A MOTION TO
APPROVE MOVED BY MELGAR? COULD I HAVE A SECOND SECONDED
BY DORSEY. MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED SUPERVISOR SAUTER
SADR EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON EYE SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR AND GUARDIAN
AND GUARDIAN EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER EYES SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD MAHMOOD EYES SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN MANDOLIN I
AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR EITHER ARE LEBANESE.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MINUTES WILL BE APPROVED AFTER
PUBLIC COMMENT AS PRESENTED. MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO THE
CONSENT AGENDA PLEASE CALL ITEMS ONE THROUGH FOUR ITEMS
ONE THROUGH FOUR. THESE ITEMS ARE ON CONSENT
AND CONSIDERED TO BE ROUTINE. IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY
BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED SEPARATELY.
>> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS ONE THROUGH FOUR
SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES
SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR FIELDER
FIELDER EYES SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN
ALL RIGHT GENTLEMEN I AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR
EITHER ARE LEBANESE WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE ORDINANCES ARE
FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO NEW BUSINESS PLEASE
CALL ITEM FIVE. >> ITEM FIVE THIS IS A
RESOLUTION THAT AUTHORIZES THE RECREATION AND PARKS DEPARTMENT
TO ACCEPT AND EXPEND AN IN-KIND GRANT FROM THE DOGPATCH
AND NORTHWEST POTRERO HILL GREEN BENEFIT DISTRICT VALUED
AT APPROXIMATELY 580,000 FOR THE DESIGN AND CONSTRUCTION OF
THE 22ND STREET TRAIL STEPS. LET'S TAKE THIS ITEM SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
SIX ITEM SIX RESOLUTION TO RETROACTIVELY APPROVE THE
AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE CITY AND COUNTY AND THE UNIFIED
SCHOOL DISTRICT FOR THE STUDENT SUCCESS FUND FOR A TERM OF ONE
YEAR FROM JULY 1ST, 2025 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2026 AND FOR
AN AMOUNT OF APPROXIMATELY 29 MILLION AND AGAIN SAME HOUSE,
SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM SEVEN ITEM SEVEN
RESOLUTION TO APPROVE THE FIRST AMENDMENT TO THE TERMINAL TO
RETAIL MARKET AND HARVEY MILK TERMINAL ONE SPECIALTY RETAIL
STORES CONCESSION LEASE NUMBER 20 DASH 0156 BETWEEN M R G SAN
FRANCISCO TERMINAL TWO LLC FOR THE ADDITION OF THREE LOCATIONS
TO THE PREMISES OF THE TERMINAL TO RETAIL MARKET FOR A 12 YEAR
TERM TO COMMENCE ON OCTOBER FIRST 2025 THROUGH OCTOBER 1ST
2037 WITH NO ADJUSTMENT TO THE MINIMUM ANNUAL GUARANTEE OF 2.3
MILLION. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM EIGHT ITEM EIGHT RESOLUTION TO
AUTHORIZE THE DEPARTMENT OF TECHNOLOGY TO APPROVE THE
SECOND AMENDMENT WITH AT&T DOING BUSINESS AS AT&T MOBILITY
TO PURCHASE PUBLIC SAFETY GRADE WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS
SERVICES FOR FIRST RESPONDERS TO EXTEND THE TERM BY 18 MONTHS
FROM OCTOBER 21ST 2025 FOR A TOTAL TERM THROUGH JUNE 30TH
EXCUSE ME THROUGH APRIL 21ST, 2027 AND TO INCREASE THE
AGREEMENT AMOUNT BY APPROXIMATELY 7.3 MILLION FOR A
NEW TOTAL CONTRACT OF 29.5 MILLION.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS
NINE AND TEN TOGETHER ITEMS NINE AND TEN ARE TWO
RESOLUTIONS THAT APPROVE TWO CONTRACTS BETWEEN THE OFFICE OF
CONTRACT ADMINISTRATION FOR ITEM NINE EXCUSE ME WITH GOLDEN
GATE PETROLEUM FOR THE SUPPLY OF DIESEL FUEL FOR A TOTAL OF
195 MILLION FOR ITEM TEN. THIS CONTRACT IS WITH PACIFIC
COAST PETROLEUM FOR THE SUPPLY OF GASOLINE FUEL FOR A TOTAL
NOT TO EXCEED OF 93 MILLION. BOTH ARE FOR AN INITIAL TERM OF
FIVE YEARS TO COMMENCE ON NOVEMBER 1ST, 2025 THROUGH
OCTOBER 31ST 2030 WITH THE OPTION TO EXTEND FOR UP TO AN
ADDITIONAL THREE YEARS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 11 ITEM 11 THIS RESOLUTION
RETROACTIVELY AUTHORIZES THE DEPARTMENT OF HOMELESSNESS
IN SUPPORT OF HOUSING TO ENTER INTO A GRANT AGREEMENT
AMENDMENT EFFECTIVE JULY 1ST, 2025 WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO
HEALTH PLAN TO CONTINUE TO PROVIDE ENHANCED ONSITE
SERVICES IN PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING AND DATA
INTEGRATION UNDER THE HOUSING AND HOMELESSNESS INCENTIVE
PROGRAM. TO AMEND THE EXISTING TERM OF
THE GRANT AGREEMENT THROUGH DECEMBER 31ST 2025 WITH
AUTOMATIC ONE YEAR TERM RENEWALS EFFECTIVE JANUARY
FIRST OF EACH YEAR UNTIL THE GRANT AGREEMENT IS TERMINATED
BY EITHER PARTY AND TO INCREASE THE GRANT AMOUNT BY 2.8 BY 2.82
MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL OF APPROXIMATELY 6 MILLION.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
12 ITEM 12 RESOLUTION TO RETRO ACTUALLY AUTHORIZE THE OFFICE
OF THE DISTRICT ATTORNEY TO ACCEPT AND EXPEND AN
APPROXIMATE $233,000 GRANT FROM THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA
DEPARTMENT OF INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS FOR THE WORKERS
RIGHTS ENFORCEMENT GRANT PROGRAM TO IMPLEMENT A WAGE
THEFT ENFORCEMENT PROGRAM THROUGH JULY 31ST, 2026.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
13. >> ITEM 13 RESOLUTION TO
AUTHORIZE THE SAN FRANCISCO DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH TO
SUBMIT APPLICATIONS TO THE CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH
CARE SERVICES UNDER THE BOND BEHAVIORAL HEALTH CONTINUUM
ENFORCED TRANSFER PROGRAM ROUND TWO UNMET NEEDS PROGRAM.
PURSUANT TO THE BEHAVIORAL HEALTH INFRASTRUCTURE BOND ACT
OF 2024 FOR GRANTS WITH TERMS NOT TO EXCEED TEN YEARS WITH
ANTICIPATED REVENUE TO THE CITY IN EXCESS OF 25 MILLION.
>> SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU PRESIDENT MANAGEMENT I WOULD
WELCOME EVERYBODY SUPPORT FOR THIS.
I WANTED TO WAIT FOR SOMETHING THAT I WAS CO-SPONSOR ING
BECAUSE I WANTED TO GIVE A SHOUT OUT AND WELCOME THE CLASS
FROM SIV LAB HOW SAN FRANCISCO GOVERNMENT WORKS AND EXPRESS MY
THANKS TO MICHAEL ADAMS FOR LEADING THAT EFFORT.
MORE THAN THAT, THANK YOU ALL TO EVERYBODY IN ATTENDANCE FOR
YOUR CIVIC ENGAGEMENT AND INTEREST IN OUR WORK.
WELCOME TO SAN FRANCISCO CITY HALL AND I APPRECIATE
EVERYBODY'S SUPPORT FOR THIS IMPORTANT LEGISLATION BEFORE
US. AND ITEM 13 THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR DORSEY SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 14.
ITEM 14 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE BUILDING AND PLANNING
CODES TO COMPLY WITH CALIFORNIA GOVERNMENT CODE SECTION 66007
BY POSTPONING THE COLLECTION OF DEVELOPMENT IMPACT FEES FOR
DESIGNATED RESIDENTIAL DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS TO THE
DATE OF FIRST CERTIFICATE OF OCCUPANCY OR FIRST TEMPORARY
CERTIFICATE OF OCCUPANCY WHICHEVER OCCURS FIRST AND TO
AFFIRM THE SEQUENCE DETERMINATION AND TO MAKE THE
APPROPRIATE FINDINGS. >> SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU
PRESIDENT MADAM AND JUST TO THE CHAIR WHAT IS THE INTENDED
PURPOSE OF THIS? >> DO WE HAVE A REPRESENTATIVE
OF B I MR. HANNA. >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
BOARD MEMBER WALTON THIS IS IMPLEMENTING SENATE BILL 937
FROM LAST YEAR. THIS IS A STATE REQUIREMENT.
THIS IS JUST CONFORMING WITH STATE LAW AND SO IF WE DON'T DO
THIS, WHAT HAPPENS? WE WOULD NOT BE IN CONFORMANCE
TO STATE LAW AND THERE ISN'T AN ENFORCEMENT MECHANISM SPECIFIC
TO THIS PARTICULAR LAW THAT I'M AWARE OF.
BUT YOU SAID THERE WOULD BE NO ENFORCEMENT.
I'M NOT SURE I DON'T BELIEVE THAT THERE'S A SPECIFIC
ENFORCEMENT MECHANISM IN THIS LAW AND IT IS A SHALL WE ARE
REQUIRED TO DO THIS. I'M NOT SURE IF THE CITY
ATTORNEY HAS OTHER ABILITY TO EXPAND ON THAT.
SO FOR CLARITY IF YOU CAN HELP ME.
DEPUTY CITY ATTORNEY RECEIVED WE ARE GOING TO WAIVE DEVELOPER
FEES CORRECT ON THIS DEFER THE FIRST I'M SORRY DEFER DEVELOPER
FEES ON THIS. >> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS
DEPUTY CITY ATTORNEY BRAD RAZZI THIS ORDINANCE AND THE STATE
BILL THAT IT IMPLEMENTS JUST DELAYS THE COLLECTION OF THE
FEES UNTIL THE CERTIFICATE OF OCCUPANCY IS ISSUED RATHER THAN
COLLECTING THEM AT THE TIME THE PERMIT APPLICATION IS THE
PERMIT IS GRANTED. GOT IT.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
PRESIDENT AMENDMENT THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU.
SURPRISE. WELL I WASN'T GOING TO TALK
ABOUT THIS ITEM BUT I SAW IT AND I ALSO HAD A LITTLE.
>> WHAT IS THIS AND FROM MY WAY BACK WHEN YOU KNOW CITY
ATTORNEY LAND USE DAYS I WAS ALWAYS UNDER THE IMPRESSION IT
WAS PRETTY BAD PRACTICE FOR LOCALITIES TO BE DEFERRING
UNTIL THE VERY, VERY END OF THE DEVELOPMENT PROCESS.
THE COLLECTION OF OF THESE FEES THAT THAT MADE IN SOME CASES
NOT USUALLY GENERALLY IT WOULD BE FINE BUT THAT THERE WOULD BE
THOSE CASES WHERE A DEVELOPER MIGHT NOT WANT TO PAY AND THEN
THEY WOULD THEN BE ALIGNED WITH PEOPLE TRYING TO MOVE INTO
THEIR UNITS. AND SO I WAS SURPRISED THAT WE
WERE DOING THIS. BUT YES, I RAN THROUGH THIS
SAME EXERCISE YOU'VE JUST DONE NOW I DID IT ABOUT A HALF AN
HOUR AGO AND AND LEARNED THAT YES, THIS IS A REQUIREMENT OF
STATE LAW WHICH I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY ANYWAY.
I GUESS I'M VOTING FOR IT THAT YOU ALL CAN DO WHATEVER YOU
LIKE, MADAM. WELL, I GUESS SHOULD WE CALL
YOU A ROLL CALL OR DO WE OR YOU SEND OUR SAME CALL, BUT I'LL
SUPPORT IT. >> OKAY.
ALL RIGHT. SO WE'LL TAKE THIS ITEM, WE'LL
DO A ROLL CALL. OKAY.
WE'RE GOING TO DO A ROLL CALL ON 14 AND ITEM 14.
>> SUPERVISOR SADR. SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL
I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER NO SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR
MANDOLIN MANDOLIN I. AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR I MELGAR
I THERE ARE TEN EYES AND ONE NO WITH SUPERVISOR FIELDER VOTING
NO THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK LET'S
TAKE THE SANSOM PROJECT MATTERS TOGETHER PLEASE CALL ADAMS 15
THROUGH 18 AND 25 AND 26 UNDER COMMITTEE REPORTS.
>> ITEMS 15 THROUGH 18 AND 25 AND 26 ARE ITEMS PERTAINING TO
THE FIVE $0.30 FROM PROJECT. ITEM 15 IS AN ORDINANCE THAT
AMENDS THE GENERAL PLAN TO REVISE THE URBAN DESIGN ELEMENT
THE DOWNTOWN AREA PLAN AND THE LAND USE INDEX TO FACILITATE
THE PROJECT AND FIRE STATION 13 DEVELOPMENT PROJECT AND TO
ADOPT THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS. ITEM 16 THIS ORDINANCE AMENDS
THE PLANNING CODE TO CREATE THE 530 SANSOM MIXED USE TOWER
AND FIRE STATION SPECIAL USE DISTRICT KNOWN AS THE PROJECT
TO INCLUDE A CONDITIONAL USE REVIEW AND APPROVAL PROCESS
ALLOWING STREAMLINED APPROVAL AND EXEMPTIONS FROM CERTAIN
PLANNING CODE REQUIREMENTS AND THE CONDITIONAL RESCISSION
OF AN EXISTING ARTICLE TEN LANDMARK DESIGNATION OF 447
BATTERY STREET WITHIN THE SPECIAL USE DISTRICT TO REVISE
THE ZONING MAP TO INCREASE THE MAXIMUM HEIGHT FOR ASSESSOR'S
PARCEL BLOCK NUMBER 0206 LOT NUMBERS ZERO 13 ZERO 14
AND ZERO 17 WITHIN THE SPECIAL USE DISTRICT AND TO ADOPT THE
APPROPRIATE FINDINGS ITEM 17 THIS ORDINANCE APPROVES A MAJOR
ENCROACHMENT PERMIT FOR EKU X JACKSON ASKEW HOLDCO LLC TO
OCCUPY PORTIONS OF MERCHANT STREET FOR THE PROJECT BETWEEN
SANSOM AND BATTERY STREETS ADJACENT TO 425 WASHINGTON
STREET 439 THROUGH 445 WASHING STREET WASHINGTON STREET
AND 530 SANSOM STREET FOR THE PURPOSE OF INSTALLING
AND MAINTAINING A DECORATIVE ROADWAY AND SIDEWALK PAVING
TABLETOP CROSSWALKS OVERHEAD STRING LIGHTING VARIOUS
PEDESTRIAN AND BIKE ORIENTED IMPROVEMENT S OTHER THAN
NONSTANDARD INFRASTRUCTURE AND NEW STREET TREES AND TO
WAIVE CERTAIN OTHER REQUIREMENTS UNDER THE PUBLIC
WORKS CODE AND TO ADOPT THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
ITEM 18 THIS ORDINANCE APPROVES AN AMENDED AND RESTATED
CONDITIONAL PROPERTY EXCHANGE AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE CITY
AND COUNTY AND OEKO-TEX JACKSON RESCUE HOLDCO LLC FOR THE
EXCHANGE OF 530 SANSOM STREET AND 447 BATTERY STREET AND THE
CONSTRUCTION OF A NEW FIRE STATION ON 447 BATTERY STREET
AND ADOPTS THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS AND ITEMS 25 AND 26
WERE CONSIDERED BY THE GOVERNMENT AUDIT AND OVERSIGHT
COMMITTEE AT A SPECIAL MEETING ON MONDAY OCTOBER 6TH AND WERE
RECOMMENDED AS COMMITTEE REPORTS ITEM 25.
THIS ORDINANCE APPROVES A DEVELOPMENT AGREEMENT BETWEEN
THE CITY AND COUNTY AND EXCUSED JACKSON ESKEW HOLDCO LLC FOR
THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE PROJECT AT 425 WASHINGTON STREET 439
THROUGH 445 WASHINGTON STREET 530 SANSOM STREET AND 447
BATTERY STREET TO APPROVE CERTAIN IMPACT FEES AND ACCEPT
AND APPROPRIATE IN APPROXIMATELY AN AMOUNT
IN APPROXIMATELY 4.3 MILLION FOR ADDITIONAL AFFORDABLE
HOUSING PAYMENT CONFIRMING COMPLIANCE WITH OR WAIVING
CERTAIN PROVISIONS OF THE ADMINISTRATIVE THE PLANNING THE
PUBLIC WORKS LABOR AND EMPLOYMENT AND HEALTH CODES
TO RATIFY PAST ACTIONS AND TO AUTHORIZE FUTURE ACTIONS
IN FURTHERANCE OF THE ORDINANCE AS DEFINED HEREIN AND TO ADOPT
THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS AND ITEM 26 THIS ORDINANCE
APPROVES A HOTEL AND FIRE STATION DEVELOPMENT INCENTIVE
AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE CITY AND COUNTY AND EXECUTE JACKSON
RESCUE HOLDCO LLC FOR THE 530 SANSOM MIXED USE TOWER AND FIRE
STATION 13 DEVELOPMENT PROJECT TO PROVIDE FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE
OF UP TO APPROXIMATELY 86 MILLION IN NET PRESENT VALUE
OVER 25 CALCULATED 25 YEARS CALCULATED FOR MEASUREMENT
PURPOSES ONLY AS A PERCENTAGE OF NEW TRANSIENT OCCUPANCY
TAXES THE CITY ACTUALLY RECEIVES FROM OCCUPANCY OF
GUEST ROOMS IN A PROPOSED NEW HOTEL RELATED TO THE
DEVELOPMENT AND OPERATION OF A PROJECT ON CERTAIN REAL
PROPERTY KNOWN AS THE PROJECT AND TO ADOPT THE APPROPRIATE
FINDINGS SIEBER HAS CHOSEN. THANK YOU PRESIDENT DOMAINS
WELL FIRST AND FOREMOST COLLEAGUES I WANT TO EXPRESS MY
SUPPORT FOR THIS PROJECT BUT IT WAS AN IT WASN'T EASY TO ARRIVE
THE CONCLUSION THAT I HAVE TODAY AND I THINK THAT IN THE
NEXT FEW WEEKS IN THE COMING MONTHS WE WILL BE HAVING
CONVERSATION THAT REALLY GOING TO CHANGE THE LANDSCAPE OF OUR
CITY THAT I THOUGHT THAT 530 SAMSON AND FULL FORCE SEVEN
BATTERY AS A PROJECT IS A REALLY GOOD EXAMPLE OF HOW I
THINK WE COULD ACCOMPLISH DEVELOPMENTS IN OUR CITY AND IN
THIS CASE WHILE IT'S NOT A HOUSING DEVELOPMENT PROJECT IT
IS A MIXED USE WITH HOTELS OFFICE AND COMMERCIAL ON THE
GROUND FLOOR. >> BUT IN EXCHANGE THE CITY IS
GETTING SOMETHING THAT I THINK IS INVALUABLE A BRAND NEW FIRE
STATION THAT IS MUCH NEEDED FOR THE AREA AND FOR THE CITY AS A
WHOLE. AS YOU KNOW, FIRE STATION 13 IS
ONE OF THE BUSIEST FIRE STATIONS IN THE NATION AND IT
IS GOOD TO KNOW THAT WE ARE ABLE TO WITH THE PARTNERSHIP
THROUGH THIS PARTNERSHIP AND THROUGH THIS PROJECT WE'RE
GOING TO HAVE A BRAND NEW FIRE STATION THAT'S BEEN A LONG TIME
COMING FOR THAT AREA. BUT AT THE SAME TIME THAT THIS
PROJECT AS IT HAS EVOLVED TODAY IT THEN NOW REQUIRE A
DEMOLITION OF A447 BATTERY A LANDMARK BUILDING WITHIN IT
THERE IS A SMALL BUSINESS AND IT DOES MEAN THAT WITH THIS
PROJECT, THIS NEW BUSINESS SMALL BUSINESS WILL ACTUALLY
HAVE TO FINALLY LOCATION. YOU KNOW I THINK THAT TO AN
EXTENT THAT IT WILL BE SOMEWHAT UNPRECEDENTED NOW THAT A
WHATEVER CATEGORY YOU CAN VIEW IT AS A LANDMARKING SPACE IT IS
NOW GOING TO BE DEMOLISHED. IT'S IT'S A BALANCE ACT WE I
THINK THAT THAT MEANS IT IT'S BEEN VETTED THERE AS PUBLIC
CONVERSATION AND WENT THROUGH HISTORIC PRESERVATION
COMMISSION IF IT WENT THROUGH THE PLANNING COMMISSION WENT TO
THE LAND USE AND IN FACT ALSO WENT TO THE OUR GOVERNANCE
AUDIT OVERSIGHT IN MY OPINION THAT IS ACTUALLY A VERY GOOD
PROCESS. >> IT MAY NOT BE SOMETHING THAT
WE ALL WANT SOME THERE ARE GOING TO BE SOME COST TO IT.
I DO HOPE THAT WITH ALL THESE EFFORTS AND CONVERSATION THAT A
SMALL BUSINESS WHEN THE TIME COMES WILL FIND A NEW SPACE
AND THAT WE WILL FIND WAYS TO CREATE SOME COMPROMISE TO
COMMEND THAT SPACE AS A COFFEE ROW HOUSE AT 447 BATTERY BUT AT
THE SAME TIME WE WILL HAVE A BRAND NEW FIRE STATION AND I
THINK THAT THESE ARE WORTHWHILE CONVERSATIONS AND THERE'S A LOT
OF HEART WORK. IT'S A WHOLE LOT OF HARD WORK
OF OUR CITY WORKERS. IT'S A LOT OF HARD WORK FOR
ELECTED OFFICIALS AND IN PARTNERSHIP WITH THE DEVELOPER
AND WITH OUR CITY DEPARTMENTS. AND I THINK THAT THOSE
CONVERSATION NOT ONLY WORTHWHILE BUT IT REALLY
CREATES A SPACE FOR THAT NEIGHBORHOOD WHICH IS ADJACENT
TO TRANSAMERICA, CHINATOWN AND DOWNTOWN AND AND JACKSON
SQUARE HISTORIC DISTRICT IT ALL COME TOGETHER IN THIS ONE SPACE
THAT IS REALLY WORTH EVERYONE'S EFFORT.
AND I ONLY WISH THAT AS WE CONTINUE TO THINK ABOUT THE
ENTIRE LANDSCAPE OF OUR CITY THAT WE CONTINUE TO HAVE THAT
KIND ATTENTION AND THAT LOVE AND CARE ABOUT NOT JUST THIS
ONE SPACE WHEN THERE'S INVESTMENT BUT REALLY TO TO
RECOGNIZE THAT ALL CORNERS OF OUR NEIGHBORHOODS IF THERE IS
THAT SMALL BUSINESS AND IF THERE'S A LANDMARK SPACE THAT
MAY END UP REQUIRED TO BE DEMOLISHED OR REPLACED BECAUSE
THERE'S A NEW DEVELOPMENT COMING IN THAT WE COULD STILL
HAVE THAT KIND OF ROBUST PROCESS AND CONVERSATION
AND THAT DOES NOT ALWAYS MEAN THAT SHORT AND ENDING RESULTS
OF NO BECAUSE TODAY I'M SUPPORTIVE OF IT BUT I JUST
WANT TO EXPRESS MY APPRECIATION OF THE ENTIRE PROCESS AND THAT
I COME TO THIS CONCLUSION BECAUSE I RECOGNIZE THAT YOU
KNOW, THE CHANGES HERE AND THOSE CHANGES MAY REQUIRE
SACRIFICE BUT THEN THEY ARE ALSO OUTWAIT THE CHANGES
OUTWEIGHS THE SACRIFICE THAT THAT WE HAVE TO MAKE.
SO I'M IN SUPPORT OF THAT AND I'M GRATEFUL FOR EVERYONE
THAT INVOLVED INCLUDING OUR OWN WD AND OUR FIRE DEPARTMENT
AND ALSO OUR FORMER COLLEAGUE BOARD PRESIDENT AARON PESKIN
AND ALSO OUR NOW COLLEAGUE SUPERVISOR DANNY SOUDER.
YOU KNOW AND OUR LAND USE CHAIR YOU KNOW CHAIR MELGAR AND OF
COURSE OUR G O CHAIR CHAIR FIELDER FOR ALL PUTTING IN THE
WORK TO MAKE THIS WORK. >> SO THANK YOU COLLEAGUES
SUPERVISOR SADR THANK YOU PRESIDENT I THINK MY COLLEAGUE
SUMMED IT UP QUITE WELL SO I APPRECIATE IT AND ACKNOWLEDGE
HER REMARKS AND JUST ADD A FEW THINGS.
IT HAS BEEN AN EXTENSIVE PROCESS.
IT HAS, YOU KNOW, BEEN AN IDEA THAT MY PREDECESSOR HATCHED
ALMOST A DECADE AGO AND THAT THIS THAT THIS BODY SUPPORTED
VIA RESOLUTION IN NOVEMBER OF THIS PAST YEAR.
SO I APPRECIATE ALL THE WORK THAT'S GONE INTO THIS.
IT IS A PROJECT THAT I THINK A LOT HAS BEEN MADE ABOUT ITS
IMPACT ON DOWNTOWN WHICH IS VERY IMPORTANT BUT I'M ALSO
CERTAINLY EXCITED ABOUT ITS IMPACT ON OUR NEIGHBORHOODS THE
FIRE STATION TO SERVE A LOT OF DISTRICT THREE, THE $7 MILLION
IN TRANSIT FUNDING THAT WILL COME OUT OF THESE IMPACT FEES
THE AFFORDABLE HOUSING MONEY INCLUDING $2 MILLION UPFRONT
FOR NEW ASIA AT SEVEN SEVEN DO PACIFIC AVENUE IN CHINATOWN.
SO I THINK IT HAS BEEN A COLLABORATION.
THERE IS YOU KNOW, THERE CERTAINLY IS HAS BEEN WORK TO
DO TO MAKE THIS RIGHT. THERE'S BEEN LANGUAGE OUT INTO
THE DEVELOPMENT AGREEMENT TO TO DIRECT FUNDS FROM THE DOWNTOWN
PARK FUND TO BE PRIORITIZED FOR HISTORIC PRESERVATION IN THAT
AREA IN THE DOWNTOWN OR CHINATOWN AREA.
AND THERE HAS BEEN AN ONGOING EFFORT AND DIALOG TO SUPPORT
THE SMALL BUSINESS OWNER AS WELL.
SO ALL THAT SAID, I'M EXCITED TO SUPPORT THIS AND LOOK
FORWARD TO YOUR SUPPORT AS WELL COLLEAGUES.
>> THANK YOU. ALL RIGHT MADAM CLERK, PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS 15 THROUGH 18 ITEMS 25 AND 26
SUPERVISOR SAUTER SAUTER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISE SIR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISE
RANDLEMAN ALL RIGHT MANDEL MAN I AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR
I THERE ARE 11 I WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCES ARE
PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 19 ITEM
19 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE BUILDING CODE TO
ALLOW AFFORDABLE HOUSING PROJECTS AND CERTAIN OTHER
PROJECTS TO DEFER PAYMENT OF CERTAIN ADMINISTRATIVE FEES
AND TO AFFIRM THE SECOND DETERMINATION AND TO WELL, SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL
ITEM 20 ITEM 20 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO URGE THE
COMPTROLLER CITY SERVICES AUDITOR AND THE DEPARTMENT OF
PUBLIC WORKS TO DEVELOP OBJECTIVES STREETSCAPE STAIRWAY
AND LANDSCAPE MAINTENANCE STANDARDS AND FINDING THAT WILL
MAINTAIN STREETSCAPES AND LANDSCAPES.
ASSETS ARE INTEGRAL TO SUPPORT SMALL BUSINESSES AND ECONOMIC
DEVELOPMENT ON COMMERCIAL CORRIDORS.
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAME CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
21 ITEM 20 ONE THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO ACCEPT THE
AFRICAN-AMERICAN ARTS AND CULTURAL DISTRICT'S
CULTURAL HISTORY HOUSING AND ECONOMIC SUSTAINABILITY
STRATEGY REPORT UNDER ADMINISTRATIVE CODE SECTION
107.5. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 22.
ITEM 22 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE
TO ADD PROTECTING SAN FRANCISCO, A NONPROFIT
ORGANIZATION SUPPORTING SAN FRANCISCO DEPUTY SHERIFFS
AND THEIR FAMILIES TO THE LIST OF ORGANIZATIONS TO WHICH CITY
OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES MAY MAKE DONATIONS BY PAYROLL DEDUCTION
. SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST
READING MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ADAM 23 ITEM 23 MOTION TO
APPOINT SASHA BITTNER AND NICOLE BOND TO THE IN-HOME
SUPPORTIVE SERVICES PUBLIC AUTHORITY TERMS ENDING MARCH
1ST, 2027 AND WE WILL TAKE THAT THOSE TWO ITEMS OR THAT ITEM
WITH TWO APPOINTMENTS. SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION IS APPROVED.
WE WOULD GO TO COMMITTEE REPORTS AT THIS TIME EXCEPT
THAT WE HAVE ALREADY TAKEN 25 AND 26 AND 27 WAS NOT FORWARDED
AS A COMMITTEE REPORT AND SO IN LESS THAN A MOMENT WE WILL
GO TO OUR 230 SPECIAL ORDER BUT IT'S STILL NOT TWO 30 SO WE
WILL ENJOY THIS TIME TOGETHER A AND WOW WHEN YOU WHEN YOU'RE
WAITING FOR A MINUTE TO PASS IT REALLY CAN TAKE QUITE A LONG
TIME. >> MR. TALKS ABOUT HOW DID YOU
LET THIS HAPPEN TO ME WELL I BLAME YOU DORSEY OR COUNTY
AND SO IT DIDN'T WORK. >> TIME HAS FROZEN AND WE GO OH
THANK GOD. >> MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL OUR 230 SPECIAL ORDER? >> YES, THE SPECIAL ORDER AT
230 IS THE RECOGNITION OF COMMENDATIONS FOR MERITORIOUS
SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND I BELIEVE
WE ARE STARTING WITH DISTRICT ONE SUPERVISOR CHAN THANK YOU.
>> PRESENT AMENDMENT COLLEAGUES TODAY I AM SO PROUD TO BE
HONORING SOMEONE THAT I REALLY DEEM NOT ONLY SPECIAL BUT
EXTRAORDINARY. MR. JOSEPH LANG LANG IS THE
CURRENT PUBLISHER AND EDITOR IN CHIEF OF ST DAILY USA
WESTERN EDITION WITH MORE THAN 36 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE
IN JOURNALISM, BROADCASTING AND MEDIA MANAGEMENT, HE HAS
BECOME ONE OF THE MOST INFLUENTIAL CHINESE LANGUAGE
MEDIA FIGURES AND A TRUSTED COMMUNITY LEADER IN THE BAY
AREA. MR. LANG GRADUATED FROM THE
CHINESE UNIVERSITY OF HONG KONG AND MIGRATED TO UNITED STATES
AND ARRIVING SAN FRANCISCO. WOW.
ON OCTOBER 8TH, 1988 EXACTLY 37 YEARS AGO HIS CAREER BEGAN
IN BROADCASTING AS A HUMBLE NEWS ANCHORS IN THE UNITED
STATES BEFORE JOINING TSINGTAO DAILY WHERE HE WORKED AS A
REPORTER AND EDITOR IN 2002 HE WAS APPOINTED EDITOR DURING
CHIEF OF THE WESTERN EDITION AN ACHIEVEMENT RECOGNIZED BY THEN
SAN FRANCISCO MAYOR WILLIE BROWN WHO PROCLAIMED A JOSEPH
LANG DAY IN HIS HONOR IN 2016 HE WAS PROMOTED TO PUBLISHER
AND EDITOR IN CHIEF OVERSEEING THE NEWSPAPER'S EDITORIAL
AND BUSINESS OPERATION ACROSS THE WESTERN UNITED STATES.
MR. LANG IS ALSO A RADIO AND ONLINE PROGRAM HOST FOR
MORE THAN 30 YEARS WHOSE AUDIENCE IS SPREAD ACROSS THE
UNITED STATES, CANADA, AUSTRALIA AND HONG KONG.
HIS YOUTUBE COMMENTARY COMMENTARY CHANNEL HAS
ATTRACTED MORE THAN 240,000 SUBSCRIBERS DAILY MAKING HIM
ONE OF THE FIRST SOCIAL MEDIA INFLUENCERS IN THE CHINESE
DIASPORA BEFORE THE WORD INFLUENCER WAS EVEN TERMED
BEYOND HIS ROLES IN THE MEDIA. MR. LANG HAS BEEN DEEPLY
ENGAGED IN COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT, PUBLIC EDUCATION
AND CULTURAL PROMOTION. HE HAS SERVED AS THE BOARD
MEMBER OF THE NORTHERN CALIFORNIA CHINESE MEDIA
ASSOCIATION FOUNDING DIRECTOR AND CURRENT PRESIDENT OF THE
US-CHINA CULTURE EXPERIENCE CONSORTIUM AND DIRECTOR OF THE
SUE HING BENEVOLENT ASSOCIATION ONE OF THE SEVEN LEGACY CHINESE
HERITAGE NON-PROFITS IN THE UNITED STATES.
IN 2020 DURING THE COVID 19 OUTBREAK, MR. LANG SPREAD
HEADED A MAJOR FUNDRAISING CAMPAIGN AMONG OVERSEAS CHINESE
COMMUNITIES, RAISING NEARLY $500,000 FOR RED CROSS TO
SUPPORT FAMILIES OF FRONTLINE MEDICAL WORKERS WHO HAVE LOST
THEIR LIVES IN THE FIGHT AGAINST THE PANDEMIC.
HIS LEADERSHIP AND ACHIEVEMENTS HAVE BEEN RECOGNIZED WHEN
NUMEROUS AWARDS INCLUDING THE BEST BROADCAST NEWS COMMENTARY
AWARD FROM THE UNITED STATES ETHNIC MEDIA SERVICES
CALIFORNIA BLACK MEDIA IN 2023 COMMUNITY HERO AWARD FROM
CHINATOWN COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT CENTER AND BEST FEATURE REPORT
AND BEST NEWS COMMENTARY AWARDS FROM THE NORTHERN CALIFORNIA
CHINESE MEDIA ASSOCIATION. SINCE 1990 HE HAS BEEN BASED
AND ROOTED IN SAN FRANCISCO WHERE HE CONTINUES TO PLAY A
VITAL ROLE IN MEDIA LEADERSHIP, COMMUNITY SERVICE AND CULTURAL
PRESERVATION WITHIN AND BEYOND. A CHINESE AND CHINESE-AMERICAN
COMMUNITY. IT JUST SO HAPPENED THAT JOSEPH
ARRIVED IN THE UNITED STATES ON OCTOBER 8 IN 1988.
AND NOW WE CAN COMMEMORATE AND HONOR HIM FOR TODAY
AND TOMORROW. YOU KNOW IT SO IT IS MY
PLEASURE TO BE ABLE TO ACKNOWLEDGE HIM TODAY AND IN
CELEBRATION OF HIS 37 YEARS OF AMAZING AND LEGENDARY CAREER.
AND IF I MAY JUST ADD A PERSONAL NOTE THAT JOSEPH NOT
ONLY HAS BEEN A COMMUNITY LEADER BEFORE ME WHEN I THINK
ABOUT HOW TO SERVE OUR COMMUNITY BETTER NOT JUST
IN SAN FRANCISCO BUT IN BAY AREA AND MAKING IMPACT.
HE IS SOMEONE THAT I WOULD GO TO FOR ADVICE AND FRANKLY HE'S
VERY HONEST. HE DOES NOT SUGARCOAT IT.
AND I KNOW THAT THE REASON WHY I WOULD GO TO HIM FOR THOSE
ADVICE IS BECAUSE HE WILL ONLY SPEAK TO ME NOT ONLY WITH
INTELLECTUAL HONESTY BUT IN THE BEST INTEREST OF OUR COMMUNITY
AND TO REALLY THINK ABOUT HOW TO MAKE SURE THAT WE CONTINUE
TO ADVANCE THE RIGHTS OF CHINESE-AMERICAN COMMUNITY
AND THE ASIAN-AMERICAN COMMUNITY COLLECTIVELY TOGETHER
. AND TIMES THAT HE SHOWS ME THE
WAY ABOUT THE POLITICS AROUND IT BUT THEN TO HOW TO SHINE A
LIGHT OF WHY EVEN THOUGH AT TIMES IT MAY BE ADVERSARY IF
IT'S THE RIGHT THING TO DO THEN IT'S THE RIGHT TIME TO DO IT.
>> SO THANK YOU. AND I REALIZE MR. LANG, YOU
SHOULD KNOW I HAVE ALL MY COLLEAGUES ON THE ROSTER THAT
PRESIDENT BENJAMIN IS GOING TO CALL ON BEFORE WE CALL ON YOU
TO SPEAK. SO THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHAN. YES YOU HAVE TO WAIT BECAUSE WE
HAVE A LOT OF SUPERVISORS WHO WANT TO SAY NICE THINGS ABOUT
YOU. >> SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU
PRESIDENT BENJAMIN I JUST WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR CHEN FOR
UPLIFTING A VERY IMPORTANT VOICE OF OUR COMMUNITY.
MR. LOWN THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR BEING AN
IMPORTANT PILLAR FOR OUR GENERAL ISMS AND EXCELLENCE OF
JOURNALISM IN SAN FRANCISCO WHERE YOUR PROFESSIONAL
AND YOUR PASSION YOU HAVE DEDICATED TO TRUTHFUL
AND BALANCED REPORTING, AMPLIFYING OUR COMMUNITY VOICES
AND CAPTURING THE HEART BEATS OF OUR CITY AND OF OUR
COMMUNITY. SO THANK YOU FOR THAT.
AND I ALSO WANT TO THANK THE ALSO THE WORD THAT YOU LEAD BY
YOUR HEART OF CONTINUE TO BUILDING FRIENDSHIP AND BRIDGES
TO CONNECT THE CHINESE AMERICAN CULTURE WHERE OUR COMMUNITY
HERE IN THE BAY AREA AND ALSO I BOUGHT AND THIS IS REALLY
IMPORTANT TO MAKING SURE THAT THIS IS REALLY TRULY MAKING
SURE THAT OUR COMMUNITY CONTINUE TO HAVE A BELONGING
AND CONTINUE TO MAKE SURE THAT WE CAN BE TOGETHER STRONGER.
AND I ALSO WANT TO SINCERELY APPRECIATE YOU NOT ONLY FOR
YOUR OUTSTANDING LEADERSHIP BUT IT'S ALSO YOUR CONTRIBUTION TO
THE COMMUNITY AND ALSO TO THE JOURNALISM.
AND I ALSO WOULD ADD A LITTLE BIT OF MY OWN PERSONAL
EXPERIENCES AS WELL. I CANNOT YOU KNOW, I CANNOT
AGREE WITH SOME ADVICE I CHAIR MORE THAT THIS YOU ARE THE ONE
THAT WE ALL LOOK UP TO FOR ADVICE AND ALSO FOR HOW TO BEST
CONTINUALLY COMMUNITY AND BUILD COMMUNITY.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISE KAISER MELGAR THANK YOU.
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHAN FOR THIS EXCELLENT COMMENDATION.
I AM ALSO AN IMMIGRANT TO THIS COUNTRY SOMEBODY WHO LEARNED
ENGLISH NOT MY NATIVE LANGUAGE AND I KNOW HOW IMPORTANT IT IS
TO HAVE THOUGHTFUL INTELLIGENT PEOPLE BUILD RELATIONSHIPS SO
THAT THE COMMUNITY CAN GET THE INFORMATION THAT IT NEEDS IN A
TIMELY WAY. AND I THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
DOING THAT FOR THE COMMUNITY IN THE SAN FRANCISCO BAY AREA.
AND I ALSO WANTED TO SAY THAT, YOU KNOW, ON TOP OF ALL OF THE
WONDERFUL THINGS THAT MY COLLEAGUES HAVE ALREADY STATED
IN ALL OF YOUR ACCOMPLISHMENTS, I THINK THAT HOW YOU SHOW UP
FOR THE COMMUNITY IS ALSO BECAUSE OF YOUR WARMTH AS A
HUMAN. AND I HAVE TO SAY YOU AND SALLY
I SEE OVER THERE ARE SO WARM AND KIND AND ALWAYS THERE FOR
THE COMMUNITY AND THAT DEFINITELY IS HOW YOU SHOW UP
IN THE PROFESSIONAL WORK THAT YOU DO IN ADDITION TO THE
INTELLIGENCE AND YOU KNOW, TECHNICAL ARGUMENT THAT YOU
BRING TO IT. SO THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
EVERYTHING THAT YOU DO AND I APPRECIATE YOU AND THANK YOU
SUPERVISOR CHAN FOR THIS SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU
PRESIDENT MADAM AND THANK YOU SO MUCH SUPERVISOR CHEN FOR
HONORING SOMEBODY SO DESERVING. I JUST WANT TO SAY THAT ONE YOU
ARE INSPIRATION TO EVERY YOUNG JOURNALIST I WOULD SAY NOT JUST
IN THE CHINESE COMMUNITY BUT YOU ARE A POWERHOUSE FOR
CHINESE VOICE AND MOST CERTAINLY YOUR ENTREPRENEURSHIP
SPIRIT AND JUST THE WAY YOU REPRESENT CULTURE THROUGH VOICE
IS UNMATCHED AND I JUST APPRECIATE THE FACT THAT I'VE
HAD THE OPPORTUNITY OBVIOUSLY TO DO MY JOB AND CONNECT WITH
YOUR COMMUNITY THROUGH YOUR PUBLICATION AND ONE THING IS
FOR SURE AND I HAD TO AGREE WITH SUPERVISOR CHAN YOU TELL
IT LIKE IT IS 100% YOU DO NOT SUGARCOAT ANYTHING AND I THANK
YOU FOR THAT BECAUSE YOU HOLD US ACCOUNTABLE AND YOU MAKE
SURE THAT WE DO WHAT WE'RE SUPPOSED TO DO TO BE
REPRESENTATIVE OF OUR ENTIRE COMMUNITY.
SO CONGRATULATIONS IN THIS HONOR IS WELL DESERVED
SUPERVISOR SORTER THANK YOU AND SUPERVISOR CHAN THANK YOU
FOR BRINGING THIS HONOR IN FRONT OF US.
I THINK MR. LONG IT'S MORE IMPORTANT THAN EVER WITH FREE
SPEECH AND JOURNALISM UNDER ATTACK FOR YOU TO BE CELEBRATED
HERE TODAY FOR YOUR MANY, MANY YEARS OF CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR
CITY. I HAVE A ADMIRATION FOR
TSINGTAO. THERE'S A LOT OF A LOT OF
THINGS THAT I FIND THAT YOU ARE THE ONLY OUTLET THAT'S
COVERING. I THINK YOU HAVE REALLY
EXPANSIVE COVERAGE AND ALTHOUGH I OFTEN HAVE TO USE GOOGLE
TRANSLATE WHEN I'M ON YOUR WEBSITE I'M ON YOUR WEBSITE A
LOT TO TO SEE ALL THE NEWS THAT I MIGHT MISS IN THE ENGLISH
MEDIA OTHERWISE SO YOU KNOW YOUR COVERAGE AGAIN IS
EXPANSIVE. IT GIVES VOICE TO A LOT OF
ORGANIZATIONS AND COMMUNITY LEADERS THAT WOULDN'T GET THAT
VOICE OTHERWISE. AND YOU'RE AN IMPORTANT PART OF
CELEBRATING THEIR WORK. >> SO THANK YOU FOR ALL THAT
AND ALL YOUR CONTRIBUTIONS. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CESAR DORSEY THANK YOU PRESIDENT OF EDELMAN JOSEPH
I HAVE SPENT MOST OF MY CAREER IN DIFFERENT ITERATIONS WORKING
WITH JOURNALISTS AND I HAVE SEEN JOURNALISM THROUGH ITS UPS
AND ITS DOWNS AND THROUGH IT ALL I HAVE ALWAYS ROOTED FOR
JOURNALISM AND THE TRUTH IS RIGHT NOW WE'RE SEEING KIND OF
A DOWN AND THERE'S THINGS THAT I WORRY ABOUT IN THE FUTURE OF
JOURNALISM AND BY EXTENSION THE FUTURE OF OUR DEMOCRACY.
SO I'M ALWAYS ROOTING FOR NEWS OUTLETS LIKE YOURS AND CHEERING
YOU ON AND I JUST APPRECIATE YOUR LEADERSHIP AS MANY OTHERS
HAVE SAID, IT'S NOT JUST CHINESE COMMUNITY JOURNALISM.
THIS IS THIS IS BAY AREA JOURNALISM AND OFTEN YOU'RE
BREAKING AND COVERING STORIES THAT OTHER OUTLETS ARE NOT.
YOU'RE LEADING IN WAYS THAT I THINK ARE INCREDIBLY IMPORTANT
TO OUR CITY AND TO OUR DEMOCRACY.
AND I WANT TO GIVE YOU A SPECIAL SHOUT OUT FOR A GREAT
DECISION YOU MADE IN MARRYING MY FAVORITE FORMER COLLEAGUE
FROM THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT AND SALLY X
SUPERVISOR AND GADO. BEFORE MY JOB HERE I WORKED AS
A JOURNALIST IN SAN FRANCISCO FOR MANY YEARS SO I KNOW
FIRSTHAND HOW IMPORTANT IT IS TO DO LOCAL REPORTING, TO SPEAK
THE TRUTH AND TO GIVE VOICE TO COMMUNITIES IN EVERY
NEIGHBORHOOD AND THROUGHOUT THE CITY.
AND I KNOW THAT MORE JOURNALISM IS ALWAYS BETTER.
SO THANK YOU FOR CREATING MORE JOURNALISM IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THANK YOU. >> AND BEFORE I TURN THIS OVER
TO YOU TO SPEAK JOSEPH LIANG, I JUST WANT TO ECHO MY
COLLEAGUE'S COMMENTS ABOUT YOU AND YOU ARE AMAZING WIFE
AND THANK SUPERVISOR CHAN FOR OFFERING THIS WELL DESERVED
HONOR. >> SO WITH THAT MR. LAO THANK
YOU. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR ALL THE CONGRESS THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
HONORABLE PRESIDENT MADAM AND SUPERVISOR CONDITION
AND MEMBERS OF THE BOARD. THANK YOU.
I WANT US ESPECIALLY IF THAT SUPERVISOR CONDITION FOR
BRINGING FOR THIS HONOR AND THANK ALL MEMBERS OF THIS
BOARD FOR RECOGNIZING ME TODAY 35 YEARS AGO I JOINED TO STAND
OUT DAILY AS A YOUNG REPORTER. MY FIRST ASSIGNMENT WAS CITY
HALL. I SET RIGHT THERE ON THE MEDIA
BENCH COVERING BOARD MEETINGS AND RUNNING FROM ONE COMMITTEE
ROOM TO ANOTHER. WHEN MY VERY FIRST WEEK I WENT
INTO THE PRESS ROOM TO PICK UP A NEWS RELEASE, A MAN CAME UP
TO ME AND SAID THOSE ARE NOT FOR YOU.
YOU CAN TAKE THEM. I TOLD HIM I WAS SO REPORTER
FROM I'M HOUR DAILY HE SAID NEVER HEARD OF IT.
>> THERE WAS THE MOMENT I REALIZED HOW INVISIBLE THE
CHINESE PRESS WAS FROM THEN ON I MAKE IT MY MISSION TO MAKE
SURE THAT CITY HALL KNEW THAT SAME DAY HE'S HERE COVERING THE
NEWS FOR THE CHINESE COMMUNITY IN 1994 WHEN I BECAME EDITOR
MAY OFFEND JORDAN ONE OF MY I DIDN'T GO EDITORIALS WHICH WAS
NOT EXACTLY FAVORABLE TO HIM AND YET HE CALLED AND ASKED FOR
AN EDITORIAL VISIT TO A CENTER THAT WAS THE FIRST TIME A CITY
MAY BE SENT OUT SINCE THEN FEMA HAS COME FOR MY WORK.
I HAVE TRIED TO CONNECT THE CHINESE COMMUNITY TO CITY HALL
KEEPING PEOPLE INFORMED, PROTECTING THEIR RIGHTS
AND SHOWING THAT WHILE WE MAY NOT SPEAK PERFECT ENGLISH BUT
WE ARE PART OF THE SAN FRANCISCO FAMILY EVEN TODAY AS
A PUBLISHER, EDITOR IN CHIEF AND HOST OF A RADIO SHOW AND A
YOUTUBE TALK SHOW, I STILL SEE MYSELF AS A REPORTER.
I NEVER LET US SIT AT A REPORTER BENCH OVER THERE.
IF YOU ARE LEGITIMATE TODAY I PROMISE TO KEEP WORKING EVEN
HARDER TO EMPOWER OUR COMMUNITY AND TO MAKE SURE OUR VOICES ARE
HEARD. FINALLY I WANT MY COLLEAGUES
FROM ST TO JOIN US JOIN ME HERE FOR MY MIGHT BE PRODUCTIVE COME
OVER BECAUSE I WANT TO SAY THIS THIS HONOR IS NOT JUST FOR ME
IT'S BELONG TO ALL NO CODE CHINESE PRESS ESPECIALLY I
THINK THAT REPORTERS AND MY GENERAL GERMAN MANAGERS HERE
FOREIGNERS HERE TOO THOSE CHINESE PRESS ARE HARDWORKING
JOURNALISTS WHO ARE OFTEN UNDERPAID AND UNDER
APPRECIATED. BUT WE MAKE SURE THAT OUR
COMMITTEE HAVE A VOICE. >> THANK YOU
. >> NEXT UP DISTRICT THREE
SUPERVISOR SADR. >> OKAY, COLLEAGUES, TODAY I AM
PLEASED TO RECOGNIZE THE SAN FRANCISCO BAR PILOTS BAR PILOTS
. >> COME ON UP PLEASE.
>> THIS YEAR MARKS THE 175TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO BAR PILOTS. QUITE A LEGACY IN QUITE A RUN.
THE BAR PILOTS WERE ESTABLISHED IN 1850 BY CALIFORNIA'S FIRST
LEGISLATURE AND HAVE BEEN PROTECTING NORTHERN
CALIFORNIA'S WATERS SINCE THE DAYS OF THE GOLD RUSH.
DISTRICT THREE HAS THE PRIVILEGE OF BEING HOME TO THE
BAR PILOTS HEADQUARTERS. OUR OFFICE ENJOYED A TOUR OF
THE SPACE EARLIER THIS YEAR AND WE ADMIRED NOT ONLY THE
HISTORICAL ARTIFACTS BUT ALSO THE STATE OF THE ART TECHNOLOGY
BEHIND THEIR WORK. FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO ARE NOT
FAMILIAR WITH THIS ORGANIZATION ,LET ME SHARE A LITTLE BIT
MORE. THE BAR PILOTS ARE HIGHLY
SKILLED SHIP CAPTAINS WHO NAVIGATE COMMERCIAL SHIPS
THROUGH THE SAN FRANCISCO AND MONTEREY BAY WATERS TO MORE
THAN 200 DOCKS IN THE REGION. THEY TAKE SHIPS AS FAR AS
STOCKTON AND SACRAMENTO. THEY MEET SHIPS IN THE OPEN
OCEAN ON ROUGH SEAS SOMETIMES 11 MILES WEST OF THE GOLDEN
GATE BRIDGE WHICH IS A NAVIGATIONAL HAZARD KNOWN AS A
SANDBAR WHICH IS WHERE THE NAME BAR PILOT ORIGINATED TO BOARD
THESE MASSIVE SHIPS, SOME OF WHICH ARE LONGER THAN THE
SALESFORCE TOWER IS TALL. THE BAR PILOTS SCALE A 30 FOOT
ROPE LADDER OFTEN IN ROUGH SEAS OR LIMITED VISIBILITY.
THEY SHOWED US ONE OF THOSE LADDERS ON OUR TOUR AND WE ALL
DECLINED IT TO TRAIN CLIMB IT. ONCE ABOARD THE BAR PILOTS TAKE
CONTROL OF THE VESSEL AND DIRECT THE NAVIGATION TO
ITS FINAL DESTINATION. THE BAR PILOTS ARE ONE OF ONLY
A HANDFUL OF PILOT ORGANIZATIONS NATIONALLY THAT
CONDUCT THESE DANGEROUS OPEN WATER BOARDINGS.
OUR BAY'S TOPOGRAPHY STRONG CURRENTS, HIGH TRAFFIC VOLUMES
AND TEMPERAMENTAL WEATHER MAKE THIS ONE OF THE MOST
CHALLENGING PILOTING POSTS IN THE ENTIRE COUNTRY.
THEY WORK 24 HOURS A DAY, SEVEN DAYS A WEEK NAVIGATING 7700
COMMERCIAL SHIPS A YEAR COVERING 160 MILES OF ROUTES.
THEY ASSIST IN DRIVING ECONOMIC GROWTH ACROSS THE REGION BY
MOVING GOODS THAT GENERATE $970 MILLION IN STATE AND LOCAL
TAXES. >> THEY ALSO ARE ACTIVE
PARTNERS WITH OUR SAN FRANCISCO COMMUNITY.
FOR TWO DECADES EVERY YEAR. THE BAR PILOTS CO-HOST A
HOLIDAY OPEN HOUSE WITH OUR FIRE DEPARTMENT WHERE THE BAR
PILOTS DONATE OVER 100 BIKES TO THE FIRE DEPARTMENT'S TOY
HOLIDAY DRIVE TO BENEFIT LOCAL KIDS.
AND LAST YEAR THE BAR PILOTS PERFORMED A LIFE SAVING RESCUE
WHEN THEY SPOTTED A CAPSIZED VESSEL MILES OUT FROM OCEAN
BEACH. SO IT IS MY HONOR TO COMMEND
AND CONGRATULATE YOU ON 175 YEARS OF HISTORY AND SUCCESS.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE TO THE BAY AREA AND I KNOW THAT WE
HAVE PRESIDENT JOHN CARLIER ALONG WITH CAPTAIN AND AND
CAPTAIN ZACH. IF ANY OF YOU WOULD LIKE TO SAY
A FEW WORDS. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH. >> SUPERVISOR SOUDER AND THE
WHOLE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS LEADERS PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN.
IT'S SUCH AN HONOR FOR US TO RECEIVE THIS COMMENDATION
TODAY. YOU KNOW, WE HAVE BEEN
IN BUSINESS CONTINUOUSLY IN SAN FRANCISCO SINCE 1850
AND INFORMALLY SINCE 1835 AND I THINK THAT WOULD MAKE US THE
OLDEST BUSINESS CONTINUALLY OPERATING IN SAN FRANCISCO.
WE ARE ALSO THE LONGEST SERVING TENANT OF THE PORT OF SAN
FRANCISCO SINCE SINCE THERE'S BEEN A WATERFRONT WE HAVE BEEN
THERE. WE'RE VERY PROUD OF OUR PILOT
STATION AT PIER NINE IN OUR RELATIONSHIP WITH THE CITY
AND THE PORT OF SAN FRANCISCO. AND SO WE JUST WOULD REALLY
LIKE TO TO TO THANK YOU FOR HONORING US TODAY.
>> I JUST WILL BRIEFLY INTRODUCE CAPTAIN JOHN CARLI,
OUR PRESIDENT AND CAPTAIN ZACH KELLERMAN, OUR CFO.
BOTH OUR ACTIVE BAR PILOTS BRINGING THE SHIPS IN AND OUT
EVERY DAY. AND THEY ARE BOTH NATIVE OF SAN
FRANCISCANS WHO I BELIEVE WENT TO RIVAL HIGH SCHOOLS.
>> AND WITH THAT I'M GOING TO JUST TURN IT OVER TO CAPTAIN
KELLERMAN JUST FOR SOME BRIEF REMARKS.
>> THANK YOU BOARD. APPRECIATE THE HONOR.
IT'S IT'S IT'S REALLY GREAT. AS SOMEONE WHO GREW UP RAISED
IN SAN FRANCISCO AND IT'S JUST A REAL HONOR TO SERVE SAN
FRANCISCO IN THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA AND WE LOOK FORWARD
AS A GROUP AS THE SAN FRANCISCO BAR PILOTS TO CONTINUE TO SERVE
THE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA
AND KEEPING IT SAFE. THANK YOU
. >> DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR CHEN
THANK YOU. PRESIDENT AMANDO MANN COLLEAGUE
TODAY I AM PROUD TO HONOR PORKY STAHL, A SAN FRANCISCO NATIVE
AND LONGTIME MEMBER AND LEADER OF THE ITALIAN-AMERICAN SOCIAL
CLUB. >> MAY I HAVE PAUL TO COME UP
TO THE PODIUM? YES, PLEASE.
>> THANK YOU, PAUL. >> PAUL HAS BEEN A DEDICATED
MEMBER AFTER ITALIAN-AMERICAN SOCIAL CLUB IN THE EXCELSIOR
SINCE 19 71. >> HE HAS SERVED AS THE BOARD
PRESIDENT FOUR TIMES AND SERVED ON THE BOARD AS THE DIRECTOR
OVER SEVEN TIMES. >> HELPING TO PRESERVE A
CHERISHED PLACE WHERE MEMBERS AND NEIGHBORS CONSIDER TO BE A
SECOND HOME PAR BECAME A MEMBER FOLLOWING IN HIS FATHER'S
FOOTSTEPS WHO FIRST BECAME A MEMBER IN 1950.
THEIR FAMILY CHERISHED IT THE CLUB AS PART OF THEIR OWN
PARTICIPATING AND LEADING THE COMMUNITY WHILE WORKING AT HIS
FATHER'S SERVICE AT THE CENTER AROUND THE CORNER.
>> PAUL HAS WORKED IN THE EXCELSIOR HIS WHOLE ENTIRE LIFE
. >> OWNED AND OPERATED KEYSTORE
SERVICES FOR OVER 70 YEARS IN THE EXCELSIOR.
>> HE'S KNOWN MOST OF THE MERCHANTS IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD
AND HAS WATCHED THE APP AND THE FLOW OF SMALL BUSINESS ON
MISSION STREET. THEY EXCELSIOR ITALIAN-AMERICAN
SOCIAL CLUB CELEBRATED ITS 90TH ANNIVERSARY TERY THIS YEAR.
>> THE CUP CONTINUES TO BRING MEMBERS AND NEIGHBORS TOGETHER
TO CELEBRATE ITALIAN-AMERICAN HISTORY, CULTURE, LANGUAGE
AND HONORING TRADITIONS, BUILDING FRIENDSHIPS AND MOST
IMPORTANTLY KEEPING COMMUNITY SPIRITS ALIVE WITH PASSION
AND LEADERSHIP. PAUL WAS ONCE KNOWN AS THE
FORMER. NOW WE SAY THE FORMER MAYOR OF
THE MISSION ST CONTINUES TO UPHOLD AND STRENGTHEN THE
CLUB'S LEGACY INSPIRING FUTURE GENERATION IN SAN FRANCISCO
AND IN THE EXCELSIOR TO CARRY IT FORWARD.
PAUL I KNOW THAT YOU ARE OUR JAM OUR TRICIA INDEX ASIA
AND IN THE ITALIAN COMMUNITY SO I WANT TO THANK YOU AND THANK
YOU. >> NOW IT'S YOUR TURN.
MY TURN. >> WELL, THANK YOU, SUPERVISOR
CHEN. I'M ONLY HALF ITALIAN AND MY
MOTHER IS ENGLISH SCOTTISH. A LITTLE IRISH IN THERE
AND PROTESTANT BESIDES. I WISH THERE WAS MORE IRISH
IN THERE BUT WHEN I GOT THE DNA RESULTS IT'S VERY LITTLE IRISH
. BUT THE IRISH HAVE SO MUCH FUN
AND THE ITALIANS AND IRISH ALWAYS GET ALONG.
BUT MY MOTHER'S FAMILY CAME THE UNITED STATES BEFORE THE
REVOLUTIONARY WAR BETWEEN BEFORE 1776 AND MY ITALIAN
GRANDPARENTS. MY ITALIAN GRANDPARENTS CAME
FROM ITALY SO MY FATHER'S FIRST BORN HERE AND WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT ITALIANS. >> WE CAN TALK ABOUT ITALIANS
BUT WE'RE ALL AMERICANS AND WE'RE TALKING ABOUT WE'RE
ALL AMERICANS. WE'RE ALL IN HERE TOGETHER
AND BUT IT'S ALL IT'S ALL GOOD. YOU KNOW, IF YOU ONLY HAVE ONE
FACE ITALIAN AND YOU YOU'RE DI AND EVERYBODY WANTS TO BE
ITALIAN BECAUSE THEY EAT WELL, THEY DRINK WELL AND THEY HAVE A
LOT OF FUN AND PEOPLE WANT TO HANG AROUND ITALIANS.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO TELL YOU. ALL THE RESTAURANTS BUT WE DO
HAVE A GOOD TIME. ALL RIGHT.
TO AN AMERICAN SOCIAL CLUB WAS FORMED IN 1935.
>> THERE WAS THREE GROUPS OF ITALIANS FOR A MEETING IN THEIR
GARAGES ONCE A WEEK SMOKE IN TUSCANY ALLEYS EATING
CHEESE, DRINKING WINE, PLAYING PEDRO AND THE THREE GROUPS GOT
TOGETHER AND THEY SAID LET'S START OUR OWN CLUB.
>> SO THEY UNITED AND THEY HAD CHRISTMAS PARTIES AND AT THAT
TIME THE WHOLE NEIGHBORHOOD WAS ITALIAN PRACTICALLY FEW IRISH
THAT'S ABOUT IT, YOU KNOW AND THEY AFTER A COUPLE OF
YEARS THEY SAY LET'S BUY A PIECE OF PROPERTY AND LET'S
LET'S BUILD A BUILDING HERE FOR THE FOR THE NEIGHBORHOOD
AND THEY BUILT A BEAUTIFUL THEY MORTGAGE THEIR HOMES AND I
DON'T KNOW IF ANYBODY'S BEEN OUT TO THE ITALIAN AMERICAN
CLUB ON RUSH AVENUE OF ALL THINGS RUSH AVENUE WE HAVE A
BEAUTIFUL HALL AND ITALIANS ALL MOVED OUT JUST ABOUT.
I'M STILL THERE THOUGH BUT IT'S NOT ABOUT THE ITALIANS.
>> IT'S ABOUT ALL OF US. YOU KNOW WE'RE ALL ONE IN THIS
WORLD. >> I HATE TO SEE THE FIGHTING
BETWEEN THE REPUBLICANS AND THE DEMOCRATS AND EVERYBODY HATES
EACH OTHER ALMOST NOT EVERYBODY I DON'T HATE ANYBODY BUT AT
SUPERVISOR CAN I JUST LIKE TO THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU. IT WAS WONDERFUL.
WONDER IF I'M JUST GOING OFF THE CUFF HERE IS HERO I WAS I
WAS IN THE MARINE CORPS CORPS CATHOLIC GRAMMAR SCHOOL PUBLIC
AND WE WERE THE WEST LIKE DALY CITY WHEN I WAS A SOPHOMORE.
SO AT THE WESTMORE HIGH SCHOOL CLASS OF 66 WORKED ON MY FATHER
TOOK ME TO WORK WHEN I WAS 11 YEARS OLD EVERY WEEKEND EVERY
SUMMER OR EVERY EASTER VACATION, EVERY CHRISTMAS.
AND I SINCE I'M 77 NOW I JUST CLOSED THE BUSINESS SIX YEARS
AGO AND I MISS IT. >> I MISS THE PEOPLE I DON'T
MISS CRAWLING AROUND IN THE FOG AND THE RAIN AND THE WIND
AND THE CARS GETTING GREASY BUT IT WASN'T BAD, YOU KNOW.
BUT THANK YOU VERY MUCH. >> LOOK FORWARD FOR MORE FUN
AND JOY AND CELEBRATING. OH YEAH WHAT YOUR SECOND JOB IS
AFTER RETIREMENT TO CONTINUE TO LEAD THE SOCIAL CLUB.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH. WE HAVE MORE THAN ONE MORE
PEOPLE DESERVE THIS AWARD. I WANT MORE PEOPLE DESERVE THIS
AWARD. >> THANK YOU VERY MUCH
. ALL RIGHT.
AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST, DISTRICT EIGHT AND I WOULD LOVE
TO INVITE YOU'VE CHUANG AND HER TEAM TO COME ON UP PUBLIC WORKS
. >> THERE WE GO.
>> IF YOU MAKE THE GUERRERO MEDIANS LOOK GOOD, I WANT TO
LOOK AT YOU. ALL RIGHT.
TODAY I AM PRESENTING A SPECIAL COMMENDATION TO THE DEPARTMENT
OF PUBLIC WORKS TEAM THAT HAS BEEN WORKING WITH NEIGHBORS TO
BEAUTIFY AND MAINTAIN THE GUERRERO STREET MEDIANS.
THE STORY OF THOSE MEDIANS GOES BACK TO THE DAYS OF MY
PREDECESSOR, THEN SUPERVISOR BEVAN DUFTY, GILLIAN GILLETTE,
FRAN TAYLOR AND OTHER NEIGHBORS PARTNERED WITH PUBLIC WORKS TO
IMPROVE BIKE AND PEDESTRIAN SAFETY SOUTH OF CESAR CHAVEZ
AND THAT INCLUDED GREENING SOME OF THOSE MEDIANS AND ADDING A
BIKE LANE. NOW GRADUALLY AS NEIGHBORS
NORTH OF CESAR CHAVEZ SAW HOW GOOD IT LOOKED, THEY BEGAN TO
AGITATE TO GREEN AND BEAUTIFY THE CEMENT MEDIANS ON THEIR
BLOCKS AS WELL AND OVER THE YEARS ABOUT BLOCK BY BLOCK THE
MEDIANS HAVE BLOOMED. TODAY THE PARTNERSHIP BETWEEN
PUBLIC WORKS AND GROVE STREET AND NEIGHBORHOOD RESIDENTS
CONTINUES. NEIGHBOR NEIGHBORS VOLUNTEER TO
WEED WATER PRUNE MULCH AND PLANTS AND PUBLIC WORKS
KEEPS THEM OUT OF TROUBLE, HELPS BLOCK OFF TRAFFIC LANES
ON WEEKENDS, WEEKEND MORNINGS PROVIDES MULCH AND PLANTS
GARDENING EXPERTISE DIRECTION AND SUPPORT STRENGTH TO CARE
FOR THE PLANTS AND TREES THAT MAKE THOSE MEDIANS LOVELY.
NONE OF THIS WOULD BE POSSIBLE WITHOUT THE AMAZING EVA CHANG
AND HER FOLKS AND THAT INCLUDES ROBERT MCKINNEY, RASHIDA
SAUCIER DIXIE LIN, NIKKI MIXON AND GEORGE LEE.
AND IF I LEFT ANYBODY OUT I HOPE EVA WILL OR NAY WILL NAME
THEM EITHER. AND TEEN YOU'RE AMAZING.
WE ARE GRATEFUL TO YOU. YOU'RE ALWAYS REALLY NICE TO ME
WHEN I POP BY AND DO ALMOST ALMOST NO WORK OR NO WORK AT
ALL AND BUT I WANTED TO THANK YOU AND WITH THAT YOU HAVE THE
FLOOR IS YOURS. >> WELL, FIRST I WANT TO THANK
PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN FOR THE COMMENDATION.
THANK YOU FOR RECOGNIZING OUR HARD WORK COMMUNITY
PARTNERSHIPS AND BEAUTIFICATION DAYS AGO WALL STREET MEDIANS
OVER THE LAST TWO YEARS IT REALLY MEANS A LOT TO US
AND ESPECIALLY RASHEEDA TO GET THIS.
SO ROBERT RASHEEDA, NICKI JOY AND I HAVE PARTNER WITH STREET
PARK STEWARDS IN ORDER TO PLAN ,PROMOTE AND EXECUTE THESE
GARDENING DAYS AND PROVIDE LANE CLOSURE.
AND SO FOR THOSE WHO DON'T KNOW THE STREET PARK STEWARDS ARE
SUPER DEDICATED VOLUNTEERS WHO TAKE CARE OF THEIR GREEN SPACES
AND RECRUIT MORE VOLUNTEERS FOR THESE GARDENING DAY EVENTS.
>> SO WITHOUT NERD CLAIRE, MARY GIDEON, COCO AND CATHAL WE
WOULDN'T HAVE SUCH COMMUNITY SUPPORT AND MERCHANT BUY IN.
THEY COULDN'T MAKE IT TODAY UNFORTUNATELY BUT I STILL
WANTED TO LIKE THANK THEM FOR INSPIRING THEIR NEIGHBORS
AND REALLY EMBODYING THE SPIRIT OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> OUR VOLUNTEERS DO THEIR BEST.
>> YEAR AFTER YEAR YOU CHALLENGE US, YOU COLLABORATE
WITH US TO MAKE SAN FRANCISCO CLEAN GREEN AND BEAUTIFUL.
AND NEXT I WANT TO RECOGNIZE MY COWORKERS AT THE BUREAU OF
URBAN FORESTRY WHO HAVE CONTRIBUTED TO THE OVERALL
TRANSFORMATION OF OUR STREET MEDIANS THESE LAST TWO YEARS.
>> SO GEORGE COULDN'T MAKE IT TODAY.
BUT HE'S ALSO ANOTHER VOLUNTEER COORDINATOR AND PROJECT MANAGER
IN MY TEAM. BUT HERE WE GO THE BUREAU OF
URBAN FORESTRY LANDSCAPE. >> I WANT TO THANK SHU FANNIE
JOHNNY SILAS PARAGON RUSHING FELIX LOPEZ SHINGO CO HORA
SABRINA SOTO DARREN MURPHY DOUGLAS DOUGLAS REED RAISE YOUR
HAND YEAH AND OUR TREE MAINTENANCE CREW THESE ARE THE
FOLKS WHO PLANT TREES ALL OVER SAN FRANCISCO.
>> THERE ARE SMALL AND MIGHTY TEAM THAT PLANT TREES AND WATER
THEM. >> AND IF YOU'VE NOTICED WE'VE
PUT IN QUITE SOME TREES THESE LAST FEW YEARS, ESPECIALLY ON
THAT 300 BLOCK. SO AMY CRAVEN LAKISHA LAW, LEO
TORRES, LAVONDA WILLIAMS, WESLEY GWEN CLAWSON CONCERT
HALL AND ADEYEMI COLLINS. I ALSO WANT TO THANK OUR
ARBORIST WHO GRIND STUMPS JASON THURMAN NEARLY NEW ANDRE
HARRIS AND FINALLY OUR TREE INSPECTORS.
THESE ARE THE FOLKS WHO INSPECT THE TREES AND DO THE PAPERWORK
FOR STONE GRINDING AND TO PICK THE NEW TREES SO ALLEGRO
MONTANER AND CATHERINE SULLIVAN AND OF COURSE NONE OF THIS
WOULD BE POSSIBLE WITHOUT OUR AMAZING DIRECTOR CARLA
AND SENIOR MANAGEMENT RACHEL JADA DAVID MOORE RAISE YOUR
HAND DAVID WHO IS BEHIND ME? CAN THE CAMERA GO TO DAVID
PLEASE? >> NO.
OKAY. MAYBE NEXT TIME THEY DID IT
THEY PULLED BACK. >> THANK YOU.
CAMERA TV. >> SO I WANT TO THANK OUR
DIRECTOR CARLA RACHEL TAYLOR. DAVID MY SUPERVISOR RAMSES HE'S
BEEN AMAZING FOR THE LAST FIVE AND A HALF YEARS AND OF COURSE
OUR GOVERNMENT AFFAIRS MANAGER IN SO AGAIN THANK YOU ALL SO
MUCH AND THANK YOU PRESIDENT BENJAMIN FOR RECOGNIZING OUR
EFFORT AND THE OTHER SUPERVISOR WHO NEIGHBORS GUERRERO STREET
ALSO WANTS TO THAT ACTUALLY IS A NEIGHBOR OF THE MEDIANS
SUPERVISOR FIELDER THANKS PRESIDENT GENTLEMEN THANK YOU
TO THE WHOLE CREW HERE AND YES, AS A NEIGHBOR ON GUERRERO, I
REALLY APPRECIATE ALL OF THE WORK THAT YOUR CREW DOES TO
KEEP THIS MEDIAN WHICH IS HIGHLY TRAFFICKED BY
PEDESTRIANS, BY CARS REALLY BEAUTIFUL FOR THE BORDER
DISTRICT EIGHT AND DISTRICT NINE.
>> SO I WANT TO THANK YOU ALL THE VOLUNTEERS THAT CONTRIBUTE
PRETTY MUCH EVERY SINGLE DAY TO KEEPING THIS A REALLY PRIDEFUL
SPACE. THANK YOU SO MUCH AND THANK YOU
PRESIDENT VANDEMAN FOR THIS. COME HERE.
COME OVER HERE. I WONDER IF WHO I HAVE AS
GEORGE THE AROUND NO HE CAN MAKE IT DO I THANK THANK YOU
AND UH AND ROBERT YOU AND EVE ARE YOUR YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
WE'RE GOING TO FIND YOU. >> MAYBE YOU OVER THERE.
ME OVER HERE. OKAY.
PERFECT. >> ALL RIGHT, PUBLIC WORKS.
THANKS, EVERYBODY. YOU OKAY WITH THAT?
>> ALL RIGHT, SO MADAM CLERK, COULD YOU PLEASE CALL OUR 3
P.M. SPECIAL ORDER? >> YES, THE 3 P.M. SPECIAL
ORDER IS ITEM 24. THIS IS A PUBLIC HEARING OF THE
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TO CONVENE A COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE TODAY
FOR THE MEMBERS OF THE BOARD TO HEAR AND RECEIVE UPDATES ON THE
PROGRESS AND IMPLEMENTATION STATUS OF THE UNITED STATES
DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE RECOMMENDATIONS PERTAINING TO
REFORMS WITHIN THE POLICE DEPARTMENT.
>> SUPERVISOR ONE THANK YOU SO MUCH PRESIDENT, MADAM
AND COLLEAGUES AS YOU KNOW WE USUALLY BRING UPDATES AROUND
THIS AROUND EVERY SIX MONTHS WE HAVE HAD ADMINISTRATIVE
ADMINISTRATE CHANGES WITH THE POLICE DEPARTMENT SO WE'RE
GOING TO ALLOW FOR MORE TIME TO GIVE THEM OPPORTUNITY TO
PREPARE. SO I WANT TO CONTINUE THIS ITEM
TO NOVEMBER 18TH. ALL RIGHT.
THERE'S A MOTION FROM SUPERVISOR WALTON TO CONTINUE
THIS ITEM TO NOVEMBER 18TH. IS THERE A SECOND?
THERE'S A SECOND FROM SUPERVISOR FIELDER AND BEFORE
WE TAKE ACTION ON THAT MOTION WE NEED TO TAKE PUBLIC COMMENT.
MADAM BUT ONLY ON THE CONTINUANCE.
>> THIS IS NOT GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT, MADAM CLERK COULD YOU
PLEASE CALL FOR PUBLIC COMMENT ON THE CONTINUANCE IF YOU WOULD
LIKE TO MAKE COMMENT RIGHT NOW PLEASE STEP OVER TO YOUR RIGHT
OF THE CHAMBER JUST TO TAKE PUBLIC COMMENT ON THE
CONTINUANCE AS THE PRESIDENT STATED.
ALL RIGHT. SEEING NO ONE TAKING US UP ON
THAT OFFER. >> ALL RIGHT.
PUBLIC COMMENTS ON THE CONTINUANCE IS CLOSED AND WE
HAVE THIS MOTION BEFORE US TO CONTINUE THIS HEARING TO THE
NOVEMBER 18TH, 2025 BOARD OF SUPERVISORS MEETING AND WE CAN
WE TAKE THAT WITHOUT OBJECTION AND COLLEAGUES WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE HEARING IS CONTINUED TO NOVEMBER 18TH,
2025. >> MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO ROLL
CALL FOR INTRODUCTIONS SUPERVISOR SAUTER FIRST UP TO
INTRODUCE NEW BUSINESS. >> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK.
COLLEAGUES SERVE TWO ITEMS I HAVE A INTRODUCTION AND IN
MEMORIAM FIRST I HAVE A RESOLUTION TO EXTEND THE
OPERATIONS OF THE SKY STAR FERRIS WHEEL AND FISHERMAN'S
WHARF FOR ANOTHER 18 MONTHS WITH AN ADDITIONAL OPTION FOR
AN 18 MONTH EXTENSION. >> AFTER THAT SKY STAR FERRIS
WHEEL HAS BEEN A BIG SUCCESS SINCE NOVEMBER 2023 WELCOMING
MORE THAN HALF A MILLION RIDERS GIVING MORE REASONS TO COME TO
THE WHARF AND DELIGHTING COUNTLESS PASSENGERS WITH
BREATHTAKING VIEWS OF THE BAY. IT HAS BECOME A PART OF OUR
CIVIC CELEBRATIONS AS WELL BEING LIT UP IN RAINBOW COLORS
DURING PRIDE AND IN VIOLETS AND VIOLET DURING THE VALKYRIES
PLAYOFF RUN. IT IS ONE OF THE MANY GOOD
THINGS THAT ARE HAPPENING AT THE WHARF AMONG NEW RESTAURANT
LEASES A NEW ENTERTAINMENT ZONE AT PIER 39 WHICH WAS ACTIVE
THIS PAST WEEKEND WHERE WE CELEBRATED THE 47TH ANNIVERSARY
OF THE CREATION OF PIER 39 AND THEN COMING SOON A
BEAUTIFUL NEW PUBLIC PLAZA WHICH IS BREAKING GROUND ON
TAYLOR STREET. I WANT TO THANK THE PORT, THANK
SKY STAR AND FISHERMAN'S WHARF COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT FOR
THEIR WORK IN PARTNERSHIP ON THIS AND COLLEAGUES IF YOU HAVE
NOT BEEN TO THE WHARF RECENTLY I SUGGEST YOU DO SO.
AND OF COURSE ENJOY A RIDE ON THE SKY STAR FERRIS WHEEL FROM
NEXT ITEM I HAVE AN IN MEMORIAM TO INTRODUCE AND I WANT TO TAKE
A MOMENT TO HONOR THE LIFE OF JO BETTS, THE BELOVED OWNER OF
SAN FRANCISCO'S HOUSE OF PRIME RIB.
JO PASSED AWAY AT THE AGE OF 86 RECENTLY LEAVING BEHIND THE
LEGACY BUILT ON HOSPITALITY AND GENEROSITY THAT TOUCHED
THOUSANDS OF LIVES. >> BORN IN BAVARIA, GERMANY
IN 1939, JO BEGAN WORKING AS A WAITER AT JUST 14 YEARS OLD.
HIS PATH TOOK HIM ACROSS EUROPE AND EVENTUALLY TO SAN FRANCISCO
IN 1962 WHERE HE ARRIVED WITH LITTLE MORE THAN DETERMINATION
AND A BIG GIFT FOR MAKING PEOPLE FEEL AT HOME.
BY THE AGE OF 28 HE HAD PURCHASED HIS FIRST RESTAURANT
HOFFMAN'S GRILL AND QUICKLY BECAME ONE OF THE YOUNGEST
AND MOST RESPECTED RESTAURATEURS IN THE CITY.
BUT IT WAS IN 1985 THAT JO TOOK OVER THE HOUSE OF PRIME RIB
AND BEGAN BUILDING WHAT WOULD BECOME HIS LIFE'S WORK.
>> HE PRESERVED THE CLASSIC CHARM AND ELEVATED IT INTO A
BELOVED INSTITUTION WHERE FAMILIES GATHERED, STRANGERS
BECAME FRIENDS AND EVERY MEAL FELT LIKE A SPECIAL OCCASION.
IT WAS HANDS ON EVERY DAY WALKING THE DINING ROOM,
CHECKING THE QUALITY OF FOOD HIMSELF, TREATING EVERY GUESTS
LIKE THEY WERE WALKING INTO HIS OWN HOME.
HIS COMMITMENT DIDN'T STOP AT THE RESTAURANT DOOR.
FOR OVER 30 YEARS JO AND HIS FAMILY SERVED CHRISTMAS EVE
PRIVATE DINNERS TO UNHOUSED AND LOW INCOME SAN FRANCISCANS
THROUGH GLIDE MEMORIAL CHURCH. MORE THAN 75,000 HOLIDAY MEALS
WERE GIVEN FREELY WITH THE SAME CARE AND QUALITY SERVED AT HIS
RESTAURANT. THAT KIND OF GENEROSITY DEFINED
WHO JO WAS EVEN INTO HIS 80S HE COULD BE FOUND AT THE HOUSE OF
PRIME RIB CHATTING WITH GUESTS AND STAFF STILL PERFECTING THE
EXPERIENCE AND TAKING CARE OF CUSTOMERS.
HE ONCE SAID I'M NOT HERE BECAUSE I HAVE TO BE.
I'M HERE BECAUSE I LOVE IT. AND WE ALL FELT THAT LOVE TO
THE BETTS FAMILY AND THE ENTIRE HOUSE OF PRIME RIB TEAM.
WE EXTEND OUR HEARTFELT CONDOLENCES.
JO'S LEGACY WILL LIVE ON THROUGH MEALS SHARED KINDNESS
SHOWN AND THE COMMUNITY HE HELPED BUILD.
REST IN PEACE, JO. YOU WERE A TITAN OF HOSPITALITY
AND TRULY ONE OF A KIND. >> AND THE REST?
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR SAUDER SUPERVISOR
CHERYL COLLEAGUES. >> TODAY I AM INTRODUCING A
HEARING REQUEST TO EXPLORE HOW WE CAN APPLY OUR CITYWIDE
OBJECTIVE DESIGN STANDARDS TO FIT INTO THE INDIVIDUAL CONTEXT
OF OUR UNIQUE NEIGHBORHOODS. >> NOW, AS WE ALL KNOW, THE
FAMILY ZONING PLAN WILL BE COMING TO THE BOARD SOON
MEANING THAT WE'LL BE ADDING POTENTIALLY MANY MORE HOMES
IN THE COMING DECADES. >> WITH THIS PLAN IN MIND.
IT IS IMPERATIVE THAT WE BE FORWARD THINKING ABOUT THE
FUTURE OF OUR BUILDING AND URBAN DESIGN.
>> SAN FRANCISCO'S URBAN LANDSCAPE IS THE RESULT OF
THOUGHTFUL ORCHESTRATION OF BUILDINGS, OPEN SPACE
STREETSCAPES AND MORE. AND AS WE PREPARE FOR THE
FUTURE WE MUST DO SO WITH SAN FRANCISCO'S UNIQUE DESIGN
IN MIND. >> THROUGHOUT THE YEAR I'VE SAT
WITH LOCAL ARCHITECTS, PLANNERS AND MORE TO DISCUSS THIS ISSUE
AND THESE CONVERSATIONS HAVE MADE ME CONFIDENT THAT WE CAN
ACHIEVE OUR HOUSING GOALS WHILE PROMOTING THOUGHTFUL
ARCHITECTURAL DESIGN. >> TO DO SO, HOWEVER, WE NEED
TO BE METICULOUS IN CREATING NEIGHBORHOOD STANDARDS THAT ARE
MINISTERIAL OBJECTIVE AND DO NOT ADD COSTS.
>> THIS HEARING WILL CONVENE BOTH THE PLANNING DEPARTMENT
AND SUBJECT MATTER EXPERTS TO THE TABLE TO ENSURE THE FUTURE
OF HOUSING IN SAN FRANCISCO IS INCLUSIVE, ACCESSIBLE
AND ULTIMATELY SAN FRANCISCAN IN DESIGN.
THANK YOU COLLEAGUES AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR SHERYL SUPERVISOR
WALTON THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. >> COLLEAGUES TODAY I HAVE AN
IN MEMORIAM FOR DIANA MOORE. >> WONG WONG LEO LANDERS A SAN
FRANCISCAN WHOSE LOVE, STRENGTH AND GENEROSITY LEFT A MARK ON
EVERYONE SHE MET. DIANA WAS BORN HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO ON DECEMBER 18TH, 1984.
SHE SPENT HER EARLIEST YEARS AND TWO HIGH TYPE HIGH.
RAISED BY HER GRANDMOTHER IN A .
BEFORE RETURNING TO CALIFORNIA AT AGE SIX TO BE WITH THEIR
PARENTS. SHE WAS THE ELDEST OF THREE
SIBLINGS WITH HER YOUNGER SISTER LINDA AND HER YOUNGER
BROTHER DAVID. AMONG THEM SHE WAS THE
TENACIOUS ONE, THE RELIABLE ONE, THE GUIDE IN THE BRIDGE.
SHE CARRIED HARDSHIPS SO THAT OTHERS DID NOT HAVE TO IF SHE
EMBRACED FAMILY IN THE DEEPEST SENSE WEAVING TOGETHER
RELATIVES ACROSS OCEANS AND CULTURES.
DIANA WASN'T JUST A SISTER TO HER SIBLINGS.
SHE MADE HERSELF A BIG SISTER TO FRIENDS, COLLEAGUES
AND COMMUNITY MEMBERS ALIKE. WHATEVER SHE HAD SHE SHARED
FREELY INCLUDING WISDOM TO HAVE KINDNESS, A LISTENING EAR OR
SIMPLY HER SENSE OF HUMOR. >> SHE ENCOURAGED THOSE AROUND
HER TO LIVE FULLY, TO BUILD FAMILIES OF ORIGIN AND FAMILIES
OF CHOICE AS SHE CALLS FAMILY AND TO NURTURE THEMSELVES WITH
LOVE. >> SHE BROUGHT THAT SAME SPIRIT
TO EVERYTHING SHE DID. A PROUD GRADUATE OF LAW HIGH
SCHOOL AND HUMBLE STATE UNIVERSITY, DIANA DEVOTED
HERSELF TO BUILDING AND NURTURING COMMUNITY.
HER CAREER IN AFFORDABLE HOUSING WAS GROUNDED IN A DEEP
COMMITMENT TO TREATING RESIDENTS WITH DIGNITY
AND RESPECT. SINCE 2016 SHE WORKED AS A
PROPERTY MANAGER AT CHINATOWN COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT CENTER
WHERE SHE BECAME NOT ONLY A COLLEAGUE BUT ALSO A MENTOR
GUIDING YOUNGER STAFF AND UPLIFTING UPLIFTING
RESIDENTS WITH COMPASSION AND INTEGRITY.
DIANA WAS KNOWN FOR HER REMARKABLE WORK ETHIC, OFTEN
BALANCING MULTIPLE JOBS SUCH AS BABYSITTING AND WORKING AT FOUR
STAR SEAFOOD ALL WHILE GIVING HER BEST TO HER FAMILY, HER
FRIENDS AND THE COMMUNITY SHE LOVED.
>> HER LIFE WAS ALSO MARKED BY LOVE.
ON SEPTEMBER 25TH, 2023, DIANA MARRIED LUIS LANDO'S WHOM SHE
MET AT CDC HERE IN CITY HALL TOGETHER WITH HIS DAUGHTER
MAZZOLI AND HER BELOVED FLUFFY COMPANION LILAC.
THEY CREATED A HOME FILLED WITH JOY, ADVENTURE AND CARE.
NOT LONG AFTER THEIR WEDDING, DIANA WAS DIAGNOSED WITH CANCER
A BATTLE SHE FACED WITH THE SAME STRENGTH AND DETERMINATION
THAT ONCE HELPED HER OVERCOME LEUKEMIA.
EARLIER IN HER ADULT LIFE. >> DESPITE HER COURAGE
AND RESILIENCE, DIANA PASSED AWAY PEACEFULLY ON SEPTEMBER
30TH, 2025, SURROUNDED BY FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
SHE WILL ALWAYS BE REMEMBERED AS A SOURCE OF GUIDANCE,
STRENGTH AND JOY A BIG SISTER AND AS SOMEONE WHO LIFTED
OTHERS UP THROUGH HER WORK, HER MENTORSHIP, HER FRIENDSHIP
AND HER LOVE. >> THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WALTON.
SUPERVISOR CHAN. >> SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHEN.
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES TODAY I AM
INTRODUCING A BILL A REQUEST TO EXAMINE HOW THE CITY IS MAKING
GOOD ON ITS COMMITMENT TO FUND AFFORDABLE HOUSING.
I'M ASKING TO BE ABLE TO LOOK INTO THREE THINGS IN PARTICULAR
. >> FIRST, I'M ASKING THEM TO
ANALYZE THE IMPACT AND FORECASTS CREATED BY THE
REMOVAL OF IMPACT FEES AND INCLUSIONARY REQUIREMENTS
THAT HAVE BEEN USED TO SUPPORT THE DEVELOPMENT OF AFFORDABLE
HOUSING. >> AS VICE CHAIR OF THE LAND
USE AND TRANSPORTATION COMMITTEE I'M WITNESSED AT A
PATTERN OF DECISION MAKING WHERE WE DO AWAY WITH THE
IMPACT FEES, INCLUSIONARY REQUIREMENTS AND OTHER
STANDARDS THAT AREN'T SO CRITICAL TO FUNDING AFFORDABLE
HOUSING. >> I HAVE SERIOUS CONCERNS THAT
WE AREN'T DONE A COMPREHENSIVE AND INTENTIONAL ANALYSIS AFTER
SOME AND CONSEQUENCES OF THIS DESPAIR CHOICES.
>> OUR CITY LEADERSHIP CLAIMS THAT ONE OF THE FUNDA ONE OF
THE FOUNDATIONS OF OUR AFFORDABLE HOUSING STRATEGY IS
TO IS THE CREATION OF BMR UNITS.
>> BUT OUR CITY POLICY CHOICES DON'T REFLECT THAT WE HAVE CUT
THE IMPACT FEES AND INCLUSIONARY REQUIREMENTS
THAT LEAD TO THE PRODUCTION OF BMR UNITS.
>> WE DON'T HAVE DATA IMMEDIATELY ASSESSABLE THAT
DEMONSTRATES ALL THE WAYS WE HAVE CUMULATIVELY CUMULATIVELY
WROTE BACK THIS REQUIREMENTS AND THIS IS ESPECIALLY
TROUBLING GIVEN THAT THE MAYOR'S REZONING PROPOSAL
RELIES ON THIS TOOLS AND DON'T MEANINGFULLY EXIST ANY MORE.
>> SECOND, I'M ASKING THE BOARD TO ASSESS THE EFFICACY OF
CITY'S RELIANCE ON ONE TIME FUNDS ALL FUNDS TIED TO THE
MARKET CONDITIONS VERSUS OTHER MORE CONSISTENT AND SUSTAINABLE
REVENUE STRATEGIES. >> WE HAVE RELIED ALMOST
ENTIRELY ON SINGLE USE FUNDS THAT NEVER GET REPLENISHED OR
RENEW ONCE USED. WE DON'T HAVE A SIGNIFICANT
CONSISTENT STREAM OF INVESTMENTS AT THE SCALE
NECESSARY TO MAKE CONTINUAL AND MEANINGFUL PROGRESS ON OUR
AFFORDABLE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT. >> DESPITE THERE ARE MANY OTHER
REVENUE STRATEGIES THAT WOULD ALLOW US TO DO SO.
>> LASTLY, I AM REQUESTING AN ANALYSIS ON THE GAPS OF OUR
AFFORDABLE HOUSING DELIVERY SYSTEM TO MEET THE UNIQUE NEEDS
OF OUR VULNERABLE COMMUNITIES AND NEIGHBORHOODS.
CURRENTLY WE DON'T HAVE A WAY TO ATTACH INVESTMENT TO ADDRESS
THOSE SIGNIFICANT GAPS AND FAILURES IN OUR SYSTEM.
>> FOR EXAMPLE DISTRICT 11. CURRENTLY WE HAVE NO AFFORDABLE
HOUSING PROJECTS IN THE PIPELINE.
>> THUS BY HAVING THE GREATEST AND DENSITY OF
MULTI-GENERATIONAL WORKING CLASS FAMILY IN THE CITY AND WE
HAVEN'T DONE OUR PART TO CREATE AN AFFORDABLE HOUSING LADDER
THAT ENABLES SAN FRANCISCANS TO MOVE THROUGH AFFORDABLE HOUSING
OPPORTUNITIES BOTH RENTAL AND OWNERSHIP WHETHER IT'S THE
WHETHER IT WOULD BE A SURVIVORS OF DOMESTIC VIOLENCE
AND ASSAULT TO FAMILIES IN OUR OWN TRANSITIONING TO DEEPLY
AFFORDABLE FAMILY SIZE HOUSING TO THE WORKFORCE, HOUSING NEEDS
OF OUR TEACHERS, PUBLIC TRANSIT, PUBLIC TRANSIT
OPERATORS AND FIREFIGHTERS TO RETAIN A FOOTHOLD IN THE CITY.
>> I'M HOPEFUL THAT THIS ANALYSIS WILL HELP STEER US WE
CONTINUE TO HAVE DIFFICULT CONVERSATION AROUND AND HOW WE
CAN INTENTIONALLY AND EFFECTIVELY ADDRESS THE
AFFORDABILITY AND HOUSING CRISIS IN OUR CITY.
AND I WANT TO THANK MY LEGISLATIVE AIDES CHARLIE
AND JACKIE FOR THIS WORK AND THANK YOU AND THE REST I
SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHEN. >> SUPERVISOR DORSEY.
THANK YOU MADAM CLERK. >> COLLEAGUES LAST WEEK
GOVERNOR GAVIN NEWSOM UNEXPECTEDLY VETOED LEGISLATION
TO AUTHORIZE STATE FUNDING FOR DRUG FREE RECOVERY SUPPORTIVE
HOUSING. THIS BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
UNANIMOUSLY ENDORSED THAT STATE LEGISLATION AB 255 AUTHORED BY
SAN FRANCISCO'S OWN ASSEMBLY MEMBER MATT HANEY IN THE WAKE
OF THE GOVERNOR'S DISAPPOINTING VETO I AM TODAY INTRODUCING
LOCAL LEGISLATION TO HALT CITY FUNDING FOR NEW DRUG TOLERANT
MODELS OF PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THIS PROPOSED LEGISLATION WILL INSTEAD MANDATE THAT ALL NEW
CITY FUNDED PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING FACILITIES
BE DRUG FREE. IT WILL ALSO REQUIRE A FORMAL
SURVEY OF ALL PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING RESIDENTS
CITYWIDE TO MEASURE THEIR CHOICES AMONG THREE SUPPORTIVE
HOUSING MODELS THAT WOULD FROM NOW ON BE A DRUG TOLERANT MODEL
REFLECTING THE HOUSING FIRST STANDARD AS IT IS CURRENTLY
INTERPRETED IN CALIFORNIA A DRUG FREE MODEL IN WHICH THE
USE OF ILLICIT DRUGS ON SITE WOULD BE GROUNDS FOR RELOCATION
AND IN WHICH ANY EVICTION WOULD ADHERE TO WELL-ESTABLISHED
STANDARDS FROM HUD, SAMHSA AND NAR WHICH IS THE NATIONAL
ALLIANCE FOR RECOVERY RESIDENCES.
AND THIRD, A RECOVERY ORIENTED MODEL WHICH WOULD INCLUDE
SUPPORTIVE SERVICES DESIGNED FOR THOSE IN RECOVERY FROM
SUBSTANCE AND ALCOHOL USE DISORDERS AND THAT WOULD ALSO
ADHERE TO SAMHSA, HUD AND NADH STANDARDS.
>> IT WILL ALSO COMMIT AS A MATTER OF CITY POLICY TO
ENDEAVOR TO MEET RESIDENTS DEMAND FOR EACH OF THOSE
OPTIONS AS WE EXPAND OUR PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING
PORTFOLIO MOVING FORWARD. THIS LEGISLATION WILL FINALLY
CENTER THE WISHES OF PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING RESIDENTS
THEMSELVES AS TO WHAT KIND OF DRUG POLICY THEY WANT TO LIVE
IN IN THE RESIDENTIAL COMMUNITY WHERE THEY CALL HOME.
AND IT WOULD MOVE SAN FRANCISCO PAST THE TIRED SHIBBOLETHS OF
DRUG DECRIMINALIZATION ADVOCATES AND NONPROFIT
OPERATORS WHO INSIST THAT CALIFORNIA'S HOUSING FIRST
IMPLEMENTATION AND PERSIST AS THE ONE SIZE FITS ALL
INCREASINGLY PROBLEMATIC INCREASINGLY DEADLY 100% DRUG
TOLERANT EXPERIMENT. IT WAS NEVER INTENDED TO BE.
AS FAR BACK AS 2015, THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION'S HUD RECOGNIZED
DRUG FREE RECOVERY HOUSING AS BEING CONSISTENT WITH THE LOW
BARRIER PRINCIPLES OF HOUSING FIRST.
AND HERE I'M QUOTING SO LONG AS ENTRY INTO THE PROGRAM IS BASED
ON THE CHOICE OF THE PROGRAM PARTICIPANT AND TO SUPPORT
INDIVIDUALS AND FAMILIES ON A PARTICULARLY ON A PARTICULAR
PATH TO RECOVERY FROM ADDICTION TYPICALLY EMPHASIZING
ABSTINENCE OVER THE LAST SEVERAL YEARS AS SAN FRANCISCO
HAS EXPANDED ITS PORTFOLIO OF PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING,
OUR EXCLUSIVELY DRUG TOLERANT MODEL HAS BEEN RIGHTLY BLAMED
FOR WILDLY DISPROPORTIONATE RATES OF FATAL OVERDOSES FOR
CHAOTIC AND TOO OFTEN VIOLENT CONDITIONS IN AND OUTSIDE OF
BUILDINGS AND FOR A WIDE RANGE OF DRUG DRIVEN PUBLIC SAFETY
CHALLENGES. ACCORDING TO DATA FROM THE
OFFICE OF THE CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER, 26% OF DRUG OVERDOSE
DEATHS IN THE LAST YEAR OCCURRED IN PERMANENT
SUPPORTIVE HOUSING. THAT'S 1 IN 4 ODS CITYWIDE A
HIGHER FATALITY RATE THAN IN SHELTERS, IN HOSPITALS,
IN PRIVATE HOMES OR EVEN ON THE STREETS.
DRUG RELATED BEHAVIORS AND LAWLESSNESS ALSO LEAD TO
HUNDREDS OF PUBLIC NUISANCE COMPLAINTS INCLUDING ONE
FACILITY ALONE IN MY DISTRICT THAT GENERATED NO FEWER THAN
654 EMERGENCY CALLS FOR POLICE SERVICE IN ONE YEAR, AVERAGING
NEARLY TWO CALLS PER DAY. IT IS TIME FOR SAN FRANCISCO TO
FINALLY START DELIVERING ON THE DRUG FREE OPTIONS THAT
PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING RESIDENTS THEMSELVES HAVE BEEN
ASKING FOR. AND THAT'S ESPECIALLY TRUE OF
RESIDENTS FROM THE RECOVERY COMMUNITY WHOSE SOBRIETY AND BY
EXTENSION WHOSE LIVES HAVE TOO OFTEN BEEN ENDANGERED BY
RAMPANT DRUG USE IN HOUSING WITH DRUG POLICIES THEY WOULD
BE WISE TO AVOID. I WANT TO EXPRESS MY GRATITUDE
TO MY COAUTHOR PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN FOR HIS PARTNERSHIP
AND HELPFUL GUIDANCE ON THIS ISSUE GOING BACK MANY MONTHS.
THANKS AS WELL TO MY EARLY CO-SPONSORS SUPERVISOR CHERYL
SAUDER AND ROAD. I LOOK FORWARD TO ENGAGING WITH
ALL MY COLLEAGUES WITH ADVOCATES AND WITH COMMUNITY
MEMBERS ON THIS PROPOSAL AS IT MOVES THROUGH THE LEGISLATIVE
PROCESS AND THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR DORSEY SUPERVISOR AND GAUDIO SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR FIELDER SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD.
>> COLLEAGUES TODAY IN THE FACE OF AN UNIMAGINABLE TRAGEDY I AM
INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION HONORING THE LIFE AND SERVICE
OF JOEY ALEXANDER AND RECOGNIZING THE VITAL ROLE
URBAN ALCHEMY PLAYS IN OUR PUBLIC SAFETY NETWORK.
>> JOEY ALEXANDER IS A MAN WHO GAVE HIS HEART TO OUR
COMMUNITIES THROUGH HIS WORK AS AN URBAN ALCHEMY PRACTITIONER A
MAN WHO WAS TAKEN TOO SOON BY SENSELESS GUN VIOLENCE SIMPLY
FOR BEING BRAVE ENOUGH TO SERVE OUR COMMUNITY.
>> HE WAS A BELOVED COMMUNITY AMBASSADOR, COLLEAGUE, BROTHER
AND FRIEND. >> JOEY EMBODIED THE VERY BEST
OF OUR CITY SPIRIT RESILIENCE, COMPASSION AND WAS THE
EMBODIMENT OF REDEMPTION. >> AFTER SPENDING 23 YEARS
INCARCERATED, HE LEFT PRISON IN LATE 2022 DETERMINED TO FIND
HIS PURPOSE. >> HE BELIEVED DEEPLY THAT
PEOPLE ARE CAPABLE OF CHANGE AND HE LIVED THAT BELIEF EVERY
DAY THROUGH HIS WORK WITH URBAN ALCHEMY HELPING TO MAKE OUR
PUBLIC SPACES SAFER, MORE WELCOMING AND MORE HUMANE.
>> ASSIGNED TO THE MAIN LIBRARY POST, JOEY WAS THE FIRST FACE
MANY FAMILIES, CHILDREN AND VISITORS SAW GREETING THEM
WITH A WARM SMILE AND A STEADY PRESENCE THAT MADE PEOPLE FEEL
SAFE SIMPLY BY BEING NEAR HIM. >> ON SEPTEMBER 26TH WHILE
PERFORMING HIS DUTIES AND ASKING SOMEONE TO STOP
USING DRUGS OUTSIDE THE LIBRARY, JOEY WAS TRAGICALLY
SHOT. >> HE PASSED AWAY A FEW DAYS
LATER IN THE HOSPITAL AT JUST 60 YEARS OLD.
>> HIS DEATH IS A PROFOUND LOSS TO HIS FAMILY, HIS COLLEAGUES
AND OUR CITY. >> JOEY LIVED WITH HUMILITY,
EMPATHY AND AN UNWAVERING COMMITMENT TO HELPING OTHERS
CHOOSE A DIFFERENT PATH. AS HIS COLLEAGUE RONALD CARTER
SHARED. HE WAS HUMBLE, RESPECTFUL
AND DEEPLY KIND. I FEEL GRATEFUL TO HAVE KNOWN
HIM, TO HAVE HAD HIM TO KEEP ME ON AND OTHERS ON TRACK AND I'LL
BE GRATEFUL FOR HIS MEMORY. >> MR. ALEXANDER WAS LIVING
PROOF THAT REDEMPTION IS POSSIBLE, THAT SECOND CHANCES
MATTER AND THAT SERVICE TO COMMUNITY CAN TRANSFORM US.
URBAN ALCHEMY HIS MISSION IS TO TRANSFORM TRAUMA INTO HEALING
BY EMPLOYING INDIVIDUALS WITH LIVED EXPERIENCE OF
INCARCERATION, HOMELESSNESS AND ADDICTION.
>> WE PRIDE OURSELVES IN SAN FRANCISCO AND IN THIS BOARDROOM
AS A PROGRESSIVE CITY. >> THERE'S NO BETTER
REPRESENTATION OF THAT THAN GIVING INDIVIDUALS A SECOND
LEASE ON LIFE. INDIVIDUALS LIKE JOEY ALEXANDER
WHO WERE FORMERLY INCARCERATED AN OPPORTUNITY TO GIVE BACK TO
OUR COMMUNITIES BY SERVING IN OUR CITY'S MOST CHALLENGING
CONDITIONS AND TRANSFORMING THEM BY BRINGING SAFETY,
STABILITY AND PEACE. >> THEY DE-ESCALATE CONFLICTS,
REVERSE OVERDOSES AND CONNECT PEOPLE TO SERVICES, CARE
AND HOUSING. THEY'RE A COMPLEMENT TO OUR
CITY'S PUBLIC SAFETY ECOSYSTEM SUPPORTING OUR LAW ENFORCEMENT
AND FIRST RESPONDERS, URBAN AND COMMUNITY PARTNERS,
PRACTITIONERS STAND ON THE FRONT LINES OF OUR MOST COMPLEX
CHALLENGES NOT WITH WEAPONS OR THE AUTHORITY TO ARREST BUT
WITH COMPASSION, RESPECT AND THE POWER OF HUMAN
CONNECTION. >> URBAN ALCHEMY IS WORK
REFLECTS SAN FRANCISCO'S VALUES, DIGNITY, COMPASSION
AND THE BELIEF THAT EVERY PERSON DESERVES A PATH TO
REBUILD THEIR LIFE. >> JOEY'S PASSING REMINDS US
THAT THOSE WHO STAND ON THE FRONT LINES OF COMPASSION
DESERVE PROTECTION, RECOGNITION AND SUPPORT.
>> THANK YOU TO MY EARLY CO SPONSORS SUPERVISOR DORSEY
AND ENGARDIO MANDELL MEN AND CHAN IS SUCH AN HONOR.
MR. ALEXANDER I'D ALSO LIKE TO ADJOURN OUR MEETING IN HIS
MEMORY. >> MAY JOEY ALEXANDER BE
REMEMBERED FOR HIS BRAVERY, HIS KINDNESS AND HIS UNWAVERING
SERVICE TO SAN FRANCISCO? MAY HIS MEMORY SERVE AS AN
INSPIRATION TO ALL OF US TO CONTINUE THE WORK IN A LIFE OF
SERVICE. >> THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD.
>> SUPERVISOR GENTLEMAN THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK AND COLLEAGUES
TODAY I AM INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION TO RECOGNIZE OCTOBER
19TH THROUGH OCTOBER 25TH AS UNITED AGAINST HATE WEEK UNITED
AGAINST HATE WE EMERGED FROM A UNITED AGAINST HATE POSTER
CAMPAIGN IN RESPONSE TO WHITE SUPREMACIST RALLIES IN BERKELEY
AND SAN FRANCISCO IN 2017. UNITED AGAINST HATE WEEK HAS
BECOME AN ANNUAL EVENT AIMED AT PROMOTING UNITY, UNDERSTANDING
AND THE REJECTION OF HATE AND DISCRIMINATION.
>> AND THIS BOARD HAS PASSED SIMILAR RESOLUTIONS RECOGNIZING
UNITED AGAINST HATE WEEK IN 2019 2023 AND 2024.
THE WEEK PROVIDES AN OPPORTUNITY FOR SAN FRANCISCANS
TO JOIN CALIFORNIANS ACROSS THE STATE IN STANDING AGAINST HATE
AND BIGOTRY AND CELEBRATING OUR SHARED COMMITMENT TO INCLUSION
AND ACCEPTANCE. I WANT TO THANK THE UNITE
AGAINST HATE WEEK ORGANIZING COMMITTEE LED BY PATRICE
O'NEILL FOR THEIR ADVOCACY AND I ALSO WANT TO THANK
COMMUNITY ADVOCATE AND DISTRICT EIGHT RESIDENT SUSAN PORTER
BACKSTABBED FOR HER EFFORTS TO BUILD AWARENESS OF UNITE
AGAINST HATE WEEKEND SAN FRANCISCO.
SPECIFICALLY I WANT TO THANK MY LEGISLATIVE EINHORN FOR HIS
WORK ON THIS RESOLUTION AND I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISORS
AND GUARDIAN CHEN, CHERYL WALTON, DORSEY AND CHAN FOR
CO-SPONSORING AND THE REST I SUBMIT THANK YOU MR. PRESIDENT.
>> SUPERVISOR MELGAR THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
COLLEAGUES TODAY I AM INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION
RECOGNIZING OCTOBER 15TH AS PREGNANCY AND INFANT LOSS
REMEMBRANCE DAY IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THIS RESOLUTION ACKNOWLEDGES THE FAMILIES AND INDIVIDUALS
IN OUR CITY AND ACROSS THE WORLD WHO HAVE ENDURED THE
INVOLUNTARY LOSS OF A PREGNANCY OR INFANT LOSSES THAT TOO OFTEN
REMAIN INVISIBLE, UNSPOKEN AND UNSUPPORTED AIDED PREGNANCY
AND INFANT LOSS TAKES MANY FORMS.
MISCARRIAGE, STILLBIRTH, ECTOPIC OR MOLAR PREGNANCY
CHEMICAL PREGNANCY HOWEVER IT HAPPENS.
THE GRIEF THAT FOLLOWS IS PROFOUND ALONG WITH THE
EMOTIONAL LOSS, PREGNANCY LOSS AND STILLBIRTH OFTEN HAVE
DEBILITATING PHYSICAL COMPLICATIONS INCLUDING
INFECTION, HEMORRHAGE, FERTILITY CHALLENGES.
>> YET MANY EMPLOYERS AND INSURERS DO NOT PROVIDE
PAID LEAVE MENTAL HEALTH SUPPORT, FERTILITY BENEFITS OR
OTHER RESOURCES TO THOSE EXPERIENCING THIS TYPE OF LOSS
DESPITE HOW COMMON THESE EXPERIENCES ARE AFFECTING
ROUGHLY 1 IN 4 PREGNANCIES. MANY PEOPLE GRIEVE IN SILENCE
ISOLATED BY STIGMA AND BY CULTURAL EXPECTATIONS THAT
PREGNANCIES REMAIN SECRET DURING THE VERY MONTHS WHEN
LOSS IS MOST LIKELY TO OCCUR. THIS RESOLUTION BREAKS THAT
SILENCE AND ACKNOWLEDGES THAT NOT ONLY THE PAIN OF THE LOSS
BUT ALSO THE HOPES, THE PLANS, THE LOVE THAT HAS GONE UNSEEN.
AWARENESS IS NOT ONLY ABOUT HEALING IT'S ALSO ABOUT PUBLIC
HEALTH. WHEN WE TALK ABOUT PREGNANCY
LOSS OPENLY, WE CREATE SPACE FOR BETTER CARE, STRONGER
SUPPORT SYSTEM, BETTER PUBLIC POLICY THAT MEETS PEOPLE'S REAL
NEEDS STARTING WITH COLLECTING BASIC DATA.
THIS IS ABOUT THE KIND OF CITY WE WANT TO BE ONE THAT
ACKNOWLEDGES PAINS, VALUES, HEALING AND RECOGNIZES LOVE
IN ALL ITS FORMS. ON OCTOBER 15TH I INVITE ALL
SAN FRANCISCANS TO TAKE A MOMENT TO HONOR THE SHORT LIVES
THAT WERE LOST BUT CONTINUE TO BE LOUD, VALUED, SEEN
AND REMEMBER. THE REST I SUBMIT THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MELGAR. MR. PRESIDENT, THAT CONCLUDES
THE INTRODUCTION OF NEW BUSINESS.
>> ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO TO PUBLIC COMMENT.
AT THIS TIME THE BOARD WILL HEAR YOUR PUBLIC COMMENT IF YOU
LINE UP ON YOUR RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER.
YOU WILL BE ABLE TO SPEAK TO THE BOARD MEETING MINUTES AS
PRESENTED FOR SEPTEMBER 2ND ITEMS 30 THROUGH 38 ON THE
ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE CALENDAR OR OTHER
ITEMS THAT HAVE NOT YET HAD THEIR PUBLIC COMMENT FULFILLED.
>> WE'RE SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO MINUTES.
>> WELCOME TO OUR FIRST SPEAKER.
GOOD AFTERNOON BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
FOR THE RECORD, MY NAME IS CHRIS WARD KLEIN AND I ALSO
GOODBYE SERGEANT KLEIN OF THE UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS.
SO AS YOU ARE PROBABLY AWARE, THIS INFORMATION WILL BE COMING
OUT TO EVERY CITIZEN IN THE UNITED STATES PUBLIC HEALTH,
SAFETY AND RESEARCH SURVEILLANCE SYSTEMS INCLUDING
ONE SYSTEM WITH CODING IS SIMPLY USING VOICE AND PHONE
TECHNOLOGY TO INFLUENCE ACTIONS, VIOLENCE AND REMOTELY
TELL PEOPLE HOW TO VOTE. THIS CAME OUT IN 1979 AND 1985.
THE VIOLENCE HAS GOT TO STOP AND THAT'S WHY IT CAME OUT
IN 1979. IN 1985.
AND INTERESTING ENOUGH I RECEIVE MY BALLOT TODAY.
I OPENED IT AND SOMEONE TRIED TO USE THESE SYSTEMS TO
CYBERSTALKING ME TO TELL ME HOW TO VOTE.
THAT CANNOT HAPPEN. WE CANNOT ALLOW THOSE SYSTEMS
TO BE USED THAT WAY. I WANT TO THANK THE MEMBERS OF
THE BOARD TOO WHO SPOKE EARLIER TODAY AT THE PRESS CONFERENCE
ABOUT THE VIOLENCE IN THE TENDERLOIN AND ELSEWHERE.
THAT EQUIPMENT ON THE MAIN LIBRARY AND THE ASIAN ART
MUSEUM NEEDS TO BE TURNED OFF UNLESS THERE IS A DECLARED
EMERGENCY. >> THAT IS COMING FROM THE
COMMERCE DEPARTMENT AND THE DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE AND THE
DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE. SO WHOEVER IS NOT TURNING THAT
OFF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS HAS EQUAL AUTHORITY TO DEMAND
THAT THAT EQUIPMENT IS TURNED OFF.
>> THE TENDERLOIN LAST MONTH THREE HOMICIDES, FOUR
ADDITIONAL SHOOTINGS, TWO STABBINGS, ONE STANDOFF.
THE MAIN LIBRARY SHUT DOWN EARLY TO AN EMERGENCY.
IT'S ONLY GOING TO GET WORSE UNTIL WE HOLD PEOPLE
ACCOUNTABLE FOR USING THIS EQUIPMENT OUTSIDE THEIR NORMAL
AND ALLOWABLE USAGE. AND ONE REQUEST IF YOUR TEAMS
ARE TRYING TO CYBERSTALKING ME, DO NOT I'M BEING PROTECTED BY
THE MARINE CORPS AND THEY WILL TAKE NECESSARY ACTION TO GO
AFTER YOUR EQUIPMENT. SO PLEASE DO NOT GET CAUGHT UP
IN THIS AND DO NOT TRY TO CYBERSTALKING ME PERIOD.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
>> FOR MEMBERS OF SAN FRANCISCO AND MAYOR OF SAN FRANCISCO THIS
TITLE OF A SPEECH AS IT GROWS ON ME ON MARCH 2024 I STOOD
BEFORE A PANEL OF GRAND JURY AND JUDGES TO PRESENT MY CASE.
MY PUBLIC DECLARATION WAS INTENDED TO HAND OVER A FORMER
PRESIDENT JOE BIDEN WORLD WAR II CONSTITUTION.
>> AFTER EIGHT MINUTES OF STATEMENT, ONE OF JUDGE ASKED
WHO SENT YOU HERE? CALL ME IN A NONCHALANT MANNER.
I REPLIED TO ARTICLE IMPRESS UPON ME VICE PRESIDENT KAMALA
HARRIS. WITH THAT I WALKED OVER TO THE
PREORDERING EARLIER IN THE MORNING OF MAGNIFICATION.
I SHOOK THE JUDGE'S HANDS ARE ON A DAY'S WORK.
>> I WALKED OUT OF THE COURTROOM FOR COO FIRM STRIDE.
SUCCESS IS EMOTIONAL STATE. IT JUST GROWS ON ME.
IN 2016, AFTER AGREEING TO WORK FOR NO PAY IN CORNWALL WHERE I
MET ARCHITECT OF NETSCAPE, MARTIN GREENBERG HOW I GOT FROM
EXPERIENCE A LIFE TRYING TO PICK UP BRAINS OF WHAT IS TO BE
MY VERSION OF TRANSPORT PROTOCOL DUE TO PTP OR CHOSEN
TO TRANSFER PROTOCOL. I JUST DON'T KNOW HOW IT PUT
OFF. WAS IT LUCK OR WAS A
SURREPTITIOUSLY I WOULDN'T KNOW.
I JUST DID NOT PULL MUCH ONTO IT.
I JUST LET IT GROW ON ME. TODAY I'M RECLAIMING WHAT IS
RIGHTFULLY MINE. A FULL FLEDGED SOFTWARE
ARCHITECT EMPLOYED BY THE CITY OF SAN CISCO IMPRESSED UPON ME
JUST SEVERAL REFERENCES IMPLEMENTATION OF DUE TP TO
MARK ZUCKERBERG ELON MUSK AND THE AND IMPRESSED OF THE
WORLD TODAY WITH A POWER VESTED IN ME AS A CEO OF PROJECT
MELLOW. >> I TAPPED A SILICON TOP
INVESTOR FROM A MY OLD PAL MARC ANDREESSEN THE FOUNDER OF
NETSCAPE TESLA WOO. SHE'S A SILICON VALLEY TOP
INVESTOR. I WHICH HAS INFUSED MONEY INTO
MY COMPANY A NONPROFIT BY NAME OF PROJECT MALLOW INTO THE
HANDS OF CITIZEN SCIENCE TO GO FOR THE OFFICE OF DANIEL LEARY
. >> I THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> CAN WE HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER PLEASE? >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS AND SUPERVISOR PRESIDENT MAN.
MY NAME IS RICHARD SD PETERSON. SEVERAL WEEKS AGO I CAME
AND TALKED ABOUT PARTIAL TAXES. >> I'M STILL STUDYING PARTIAL
TAXES AND WILL BRING A MORE THOROUGH REPORT TO YOU THE NEXT
TIME I MEET. I HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO BE HERE
FOR THE LAST COUPLE OF MEETINGS AND THE IMPORTANCE OF PARCEL
TAXES TO THE HOMEOWNER ARE SUBSTANTIAL.
THE PORTIONS OF PARCEL TAXES TO DOWNTOWN ARE IMPORTANT BUT NOT
SUBSTANTIAL. >> I WANT TO ADDRESS THIS
BECAUSE THIS THE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO DOES HAVE DATABASES
NOT ONLY OF PARCELS OWN BUT IT HAS DATABASES OF OF PARCELS
DEFINED BY SIZE AND BY A HOMEOWNER HOMEOWNERS
AND WHETHER THEY'RE OCCUPIED, WHETHER THEY'RE NOT OCCUPIED
AND A THOROUGH EXAMINATION OF THIS DATABASE NEEDS TO BE DONE
TO DETERMINE WHO'S PAYING FOR WHAT.
AND I DON'T WANT THE WEST SIDE AND ACTUALLY THE REST OF THE
CITY WHO ARE HOMEOWNERS OR AT LEAST HAVE AN INTEREST IN A
HOME WHICH THEY MAY BE ACTUALLY RENTING OUT TO TO LIVE
IN ANOTHER HOME OR THEY'RE STILL HOMEOWNERS.
SO IN ANY EVENT, NEXT WEEK I'LL TRY AND GET A MORE THOROUGH
REPORT AND 1 OR 2 A SHOUT OUT TO MIMI HAAS AND SORRY YOU
MISSED A GREAT PARTY. I GUESS YOUR SON DIDN'T WANT
YOU TO ATTEND. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
BEFORE THE NEXT SPEAKER, IF THERE ARE ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF
THE PUBLIC WHO WOULD LIKE TO ADDRESS THE BOARD DURING
GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT PLEASE STEP OVER TO YOUR RIGHT HAND
SIDE OTHERWISE THIS WILL BE OUR LAST SPEAKER.
ALL RIGHT. WELCOME.
>> SO THE PROBLEM WITH THIS PUBLIC COMMENTS IS THAT IT
SEEMS YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU ARE TALKING ABOUT.
WHY ARE YOU LEAVING THE HOUSE? YOU SHOULD LISTEN TO WHAT IS
BEING SAID. >> OKAY.
IF THESE GUYS ARE LOOK THE DOWN IS BECAUSE THEY ARE PEDOPHILES
WORKING AT THE AT THE VERY LEAST FOR PEDOPHILES.
>> OKAY. LET'S A QUICK REMINDER NO
MATTER WHO YOU ARE OR WHERE YOU COME FROM, WHAT YOU DO IS ALL
THAT MATTERS. >> SO EVEN IF YOU COME FROM
ANOTHER PLANET, WE DON'T CARE. WE DON'T WANT PEDOPHILES
ANYWHERE IN TODAY'S CIVILIZATION WHICH IS GOING
VERY USUAL TO THE NOW IF ONLY IT WAS JUST IT WILL JUST
PEDOPHILIA YOU KNOW WHERE IT LEADS TO CHILD TRAFFICKING,
THE KIDS SACRIFICE BY WHATEVER SEX WE DON'T CARE.
IT'S OUT OF THE QUESTION. >> WE ACCEPT THIS.
WE ARE 99.9% HERE TO SAY YEAH, RED LINE END OF THIS STORY NO,
WE NEED TO ADDRESS THAT. WHY IS THIS SUPER AS THE GOOD
SUPPOSED GOOD ELEMENTS WHICH IS ABSOLUTELY NOT THE CASE NOT
ADDRESSING THIS IT'S NOT IMPORTANT ENOUGH.
WHY HAS THE MAINSTREAM MEDIA NOT ADDRESSING THIS?
>> IT'S NOT IMPORTANT ENOUGH. OH REALLY?
>> SO MY MISSION KEEPS GOING ON AND NOW DEFINITELY I'M
TARGETING THE PEDOPHILES. WHAT YOU'RE GOING TO DO ABOUT
IT ACCUSED ME OF PROTECTING THE KIDS.
ACCUSING ME OF WHAT EXACTLY ABOUT FROM YOU BEING A
PEDOPHILE YOURSELF. ARE THERE ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF
THE PUBLIC WHO WOULD LIKE TO ADDRESS THE BOARD DURING
GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT? >> ALL RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT.
ALL RIGHT. PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED.
MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO OUR FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE
REFERENCE AGENDA ITEMS 30 THROUGH 38 ITEM 30 THROUGH 38
WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE THE
UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON
FIRST APPEARANCE TODAY. ALTERNATIVELY A MEMBER MAY
REQUIRE A RESOLUTION ON FIRST APPEARANCE TO GO TO COMMITTEE.
>> MADAM CLERK, COULD YOU CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS 30 THROUGH 38
SUPERVISOR SAUTER SAUTER EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON ABSENT SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES
SUPERVISOR AND GAUDIO IN GAUDIO I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
SUPERVISOR MAHMUT MY MOMENT I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN I
RANDLEMAN I AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR EITHER OR TONIGHT
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK DO YOU HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS?
>> I HAVE NONE TO REPORT. MR. PRESIDENT, COULD YOU PLEASE
READ THE IN MEMORIAM? >> TODAY'S MEETING WILL BE
ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUAL
PLEASE. ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR SAUTER
FOR THE LATE MR. JOE BETTS ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR WALTON FOR
THE LATE DIANA MOON RONG LIAO ORLANDO'S AND ON BEHALF OF HALF
OF SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD FOR THE LATE MR. JOEY ALEXANDER.
AND I BELIEVE THAT BRINGS US TO THE END OF OUR AGENDA MADAM
CLERK IS THERE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS BEFORE US TODAY?
>> THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS FOR TODAY.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK WE ARE ADJOURNED.
ASSAF SAFIR GOV TV, SAN FRANCISCO GOVERNMENT TELEVISION